<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-20T08:29:38+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MrPowerScripts</title><subtitle>Learn. Code. Grow.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Automated Reality Channel Ep2 Planning</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-two/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automated Reality Channel Ep2 Planning" /><published>2020-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-20T08:19:56+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-two/">&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-one/&quot;&gt;a single episode of the automated reality channel&lt;/a&gt; processed and published live. It put waaaaay too much effort into something that probably isn’t going to go anywhere. It worked through! I did get episode 1 out the door, but it didn’t reach the project’s real goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to collaborate with content creators to create the content assets that the episodes used. Instead, I had it sing mary had a little lamb, and I showed off my atrocious paint.net skills. For episode two, I would like to accomplish the actual goal. It’s collaborating time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most significant part of the “actual goal” was that paying content creators would happen through the Patreon donations. I even &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/mrps-discord-powerbot&quot;&gt;set up a bot&lt;/a&gt; so that people who were Patreon supporters could vote on ideas for the videos. Allowing people who were funding the content creation to have a say in how that content was created. But there’s not enough community or project interest to make that work. And I had no Patreon supports to help fund the content creations or vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I got my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/MrPowerScripts&quot;&gt;Patreon supporter&lt;/a&gt;!!! Shout out to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Asgaroth 😼&lt;/code&gt; on Discord. So, we have a budget now. Of $5 lol. It’s not much, but maybe it can help us reach the goal! Even if it’s as simple as &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-one/&quot;&gt;episode one was&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, I’m going to try &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration&quot;&gt;starting small and iterating&lt;/a&gt;. I would like to find an artist to create two images of - well, they can be anything. As long as those things can talk. And find someone to write a short narrative between the two characters. Are you a writer or an artist who thinks it would be cool to be part of episode 2 even though we obviously have a tiny budget? Join us on discord and have a chat with us! https://bit.ly/mrps-discord&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">I was pretty happy to get a single episode of the automated reality channel processed and published live. It put waaaaay too much effort into something that probably isn’t going to go anywhere. It worked through! I did get episode 1 out the door, but it didn’t reach the project’s real goal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MrPowerScripts.com is a Progressive Web App (PWA)</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/my-pwa-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MrPowerScripts.com is a Progressive Web App (PWA)" /><published>2020-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-13T18:18:47+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/my-pwa-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/my-pwa-website/">&lt;p&gt;I finally did it. MrPowerScripts.com is now a Progressive Web App. Did it take long? Nope. A couple of hours. I was trying to do it from memory. It should have taken about 20 minutes. Whoops. So it’s there, it’s working, it’s incredible, and what the hell is a PWA?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-progressive-web-app-pwa&quot;&gt;What is a progressive web app? (PWA)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ever surf a website, and you like the content? And you would love to get notifications about when new content is released? Or the ability to interact with the site offline?  So you check to see if they have an app, and if you’re lucky, they do! Cause that’s all the stuff that apps do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why do you need to download an entirely new app? The content was right there already. Native apps do provide additional advantages. They have access to local resources, processes can run in the background. You can’t do all that with a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the content was RIGHT THERE ALREADY. Why do I have to open up a different app to download a new app to get a better experience with the content I was literally just looking at?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you could get the benefits of a native app directly from the website itself? So users click a button on your website that turns the site into a native app type of experience. That’s what a Progressive Web App does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWA support comes directly from browsers, so they work on both mobile and desktop. Progressive web apps turn your website into a native app-like experience on mobile, and they can also be installed as a “desktop app.” on your computer. Not every browser supports this feature. For instance, Chrome fully supports Progressive Web Apps on mobile and desktop versions. Firefox mobile has some support for PWAs, but they’ve had a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1407202&quot;&gt;three-year-old open issue&lt;/a&gt; for adding support in their desktop version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see which browsers support the required &lt;a href=&quot;https://caniuse.com/#search=PWA&quot;&gt;features for PWAs here&lt;/a&gt;. The interesting part is that the Microsoft Edge browser has full support for PWAs. In contrast, Apple’s Safari browser has no support. Why is that interesting? If you read about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_web_application&quot;&gt;history of PWAs&lt;/a&gt; they were conceptualized as the first “app” experience on the iPhone. Though they faded out of favor for the “native” solution, we’re now using. iPhone apps were supposed to be web apps build with basic HTML, CSS, and javascript through AJAX calls. Despite dragging along through the years, there’s a wide range of growing use and support for PWAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-advantages-of-a-pwa-vs-native-app&quot;&gt;What are the advantages of a PWA vs. Native app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native apps will always perform better, but many types of websites can benefit from adding PWA support. Such as content-focused sites, like news outlets. Adding PWA support will let users add your “web app” to their mobile home screen or desktop shortcuts for quick access. It also allows your website to open up as a full screen. So to the user, it will have an app-like experience. They can access it with the click of a button, and they’ll have the full phone real estate to view the content like a native app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, through the use of a service worker, you can enable various caching strategies, so that content can be cached for offline viewing. Or the content can even be updated in the background. Allowing for the new content to open quickly. New standards like Trusted Web Activity (TWA) and tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa/&quot;&gt;Bubblewrap by Google Chrome Labs team&lt;/a&gt; enable you to quickly turn your PWA website into an APK. Then you can upload your PWA APK to the Google Play store, where people can download it like a real native app. Also, like native apps, you’ll be able to send mobile and desktop notifications. Again, like a real native app!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, we’ll see more support for Progressive Web Apps, as they help bridge the gap between native and web experiences. With the use of good old fashioned Javascript, HTML, and CSS. Native apps will always have their place because of the performance and resource limitations of PWAs. But you still have access to a lot of great features like notifications, and offline viewing. Also, PWAs can be installed from desktop browsers with a simple click. Can you install a play store app on your desktop that easily? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pwas-are-here-to-stay&quot;&gt;PWAs are here to stay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWAs aren’t going to go away any time soon, and the support is only growing. Many major websites like Twitter, Facebook, and popular open-source projects like Discourse already support PWAs. Exciting tools like Bubblewrap will help increase the versatility of PWAs. And we’ll likely continue to see standards like TWA develop to blur the lines between the native app and PWA experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need help turning your website into a PWA? Join me &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/mrps-discord.&quot;&gt;on Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">I finally did it. MrPowerScripts.com is now a Progressive Web App. Did it take long? Nope. A couple of hours. I was trying to do it from memory. It should have taken about 20 minutes. Whoops. So it’s there, it’s working, it’s incredible, and what the hell is a PWA?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Simple tips for great tutorial videos</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/tutorial-video-tips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simple tips for great tutorial videos" /><published>2020-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-10T10:16:31+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/tutorial-video-tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/tutorial-video-tips/">&lt;p&gt;So I’ve had my youtube channel for over eight years now. Am I a “YouTuber”? Not really. The channel is pretty small, and I don’t post content as often as I used to. Have I improved in those eight years? You’re damn right, and that’s what I really love most about the channel. My hard work is on display. I figured it was a good time to critique my first video and share some of the things I learned about creating tutorial videos on youtube.
&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;2pGEpfnCshg&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I created my first video, I didn’t really know anything about video editing, recording audio, performing format conversions, how youtube worked. Basically, I didn’t know anything. I scrambled enough information together through the internet to put together a simple tutorial that shared a Powershell cheat sheet that I used. Not very groundbreaking, but I had to start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learned-making-tutorial-videos&quot;&gt;What I learned making tutorial videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick list of tips that will help you create great tutorial videos. Obviously, I have my own sort of approach with making tutorial videos. I like to focus on showing code, or simple images that may help illustrate a point. Everyone has their own style, and everyone has style preferences. So, if your style is different than mine these suggestions may not be helpful, but maybe they’ll help you consider some ideas you haven’t thought of already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Good audio is critical and poor sound is distracting. You want your voice to be clear and consistent throughout the video and without random background noises that detracts from the experience. It’s worth investing in all the new mid-range condenser mics available these days. It will make a huge difference. Also, learning how to apply filters like condensers and noise limiters can drastically improve the performance of even lower range audio devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your voice is audio. How you talk matters. Speak clearly, and project your voice. It may seem weird projecting your voice in an empty room, but that extra kick can improve the video experience. If you sound excited and interested in the content, it will appear more exciting and interesting. This can take a lot of practice, but the results are worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make it mobile-friendly. Mobile media consumption far surpasses desktop consumption. If what your showing can’t be viewed through mobile, then you’re leaving a lot of potential viewers out. Increase font sizes, zoom in with browsers. Whatever you need to do to make the content your showing clear on mobile should be done.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do favors with your editing. You can save people a lot of time with your editing. I’ve been able to cut a full five minutes out of videos that were just filled with pauses and “umms” that distracted from the experience and wasted time. People are watching your tutorial so they can do something, and the faster you can give them the information they need, the faster they can get back to doing that thing. Nobody has ever complained about weird cuts or the mouse jumpting around because I removed a couple seconds of the video in editing. .But I’ve received a lot of praise for how clean and concise my videos are since I began improving my editing process. A bit of extra time editing can save tons of time for viewers through the life of the video.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep adding to this list as I remember more details I’ve found helpful over the years. It’s essential to go back and critique our own works if we want to continue improving. Am I the best video creator on the planet? Not even close. But the time spent on this hobby has helped me in many ways. Every new video I created was an opportunity to analyze my own efforts and established a new baseline for me to improve upon. And the proof is there. It took me eight years to go from bad to OK, and I’m sure I’ll learn about more I can improve upon in the next eight years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">So I’ve had my youtube channel for over eight years now. Am I a “YouTuber”? Not really. The channel is pretty small, and I don’t post content as often as I used to. Have I improved in those eight years? You’re damn right, and that’s what I really love most about the channel. My hard work is on display. I figured it was a good time to critique my first video and share some of the things I learned about creating tutorial videos on youtube.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Feng Shui Bracelet - The greatest youtube commercial ever</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/feng-shui-bracelet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feng Shui Bracelet - The greatest youtube commercial ever" /><published>2020-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/feng-shui-bracelet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/feng-shui-bracelet/">&lt;p&gt;Do you want to learn more about Feng Shui and how to use it to shake $20 from people’s pockets? Well, I have the deal of a lifetime for you. Reading this blog post is going to unlock real wealth and happiness in your life. Not that fake knock of wealth and happiness. So let’s learn more about Feng Shui and how you can attain everything you’ve ever wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-youtube-commercial-is-going-to-change-your-life&quot;&gt;This youtube commercial is going to change your life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across this life-changing commercial while trying to watch something else. I forget what it was, but it wasn’t going to change my life like this commercial did. The ad starts off with a man asking me if I’ve heard about Feng Shui and how it can affect my energy flow. I have, but the exhilarating background music makes me feel like I’m about to learn more than I could imagine. Noel here seems pretty confident he’s about to change my life. Let’s do this, Noel. Lay some Feng Shui game down on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;to5llr46LhA&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;keep-your-eye-on-the-bar&quot;&gt;Keep your eye on the bar&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully this Feng Shui commercial included a flashing bar above narration text displayed on the screen. My eyes kept wandering, but the bar helped keep me focused on the explanatory captions. It also included helpful choices for words and phrases highlighted in yellow that really emphasized the positive aspects of Feng Shui. But don’t let it totally distract you from the beautiful, relevant b-rolls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;free-feng-shui-home-office-tips&quot;&gt;Free Feng Shui home office tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video, released Nov 3, 2019, lets us know that Feng Shui originated in China. Then two months later, the coronavirus, which also came from China, spread to the world. Having people trapped at home would make them more likely to see these Feng Shui adverts and be susceptible to messages of increasing wealth and prosperity. Am I saying this company deliberately spread coronavirus so people will care more about Feng Shui? Yes, it’s entirely possible given how 2020 has played out so far. It would be the least surprising thing at this point. But can you really be mad at them? They’re about to give away Feng Shui tips FOR FREE. We’re getting a great deal here, people. So here are your 5 free Feng Shui home office tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always sit so there is a solid wall behind your back. This ensures that you have support in your life. Never sit with your back towards the window.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Aways play face machines, telephone, computers, and cash registers in the southeast wealth sector to attract more prospective businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Arrange your desk so you always have a clear view of the door, preferably facing the door. If it is impossible to arrange, then hang a small mirror so you can clearly see the reflection of the door.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Never put a shelf over your desk. The shelf symbolizes the burdens of the world coming down upon you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try to keep sharp items such as paper cutters, scissors, or any sharp corners of a machine away from the desk. Make sure they are not pointing at the desk. Keep all the sharp objects hidden away from view in a drawer or closet. The sharp edges symbolize the cutting of a knife, which is a disapproving finger pointing at you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AMAZING. Five free Feng Shui tips for your home office. You’re probably thinking all that sounds like a load of horse shit, but that’s exactly what someone with an empty southeast wealth sector would think. Loser. I even sawed off all the corners of my desk to be extra safe. But what can we do outside of our home office? I need to take this magical energy with me EVERYWHERE I go. Is it possible? Can it be? You’re damn right it’s possible, and the advertisement doesn’t waste time to jump right into the alternatives, like the Feng Shui Black Obsidian Bracelet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feng-shui-black-obsidian-bracelet&quot;&gt;Feng Shui Black Obsidian Bracelet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy shit, you can literally carry Feng Shui around on your wrist with the Feng Shui Black Obsidian Bracelet. The bracelet is made of two POWERFUL talismans. First, the Pixiu talisman, which is also known as Pi Yao. The other element is black Obsidian. Wait, that’s not two talismans. You just called it an element, where is the other talisman? WHO CARES let’s go over some benefits of Pixiu and black Obsidian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attract-fortune-and-wealth-with-pixiu-talisman&quot;&gt;Attract fortune and wealth with Pixiu talisman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video tells us Pixiu is known to bring fortune and attract wealth. I mean those are kinda the same thing, right? I’m not sure why you said the same thing in two different ways, but I like the sound of both of them. This is combo deal talisman. Incredible two for one talisman value. Then there’s the black Obsidian, which is known to give protection and shield against negativity. Which is so important in this day and age where haters are everywhere. Like haters in the video youtube comments who bought the bracelet and found it didn’t do anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/feng-shui-comments.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;block-out-your-haters&quot;&gt;Block out your haters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This negative energy needs to be blocked out, and thankfully the bracelet has that critical Obsidian element. The video also goes on to state that Black Obsidian is known to increase self-control and makes one embrace their true self. Which might be why those people bought this bracelet in the first place, they simply didn’t have the self-control they needed. And now, which this bracelet, they definitely won’t make any further impulsive decisions. Truly amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most amazing part of all this is that Noel discovered the bracelet when he met Master Xi. See, Noel was a garbage collector before Master Xi put him onto the Feng Shui Black Obsidian bracelet. Noel found a wallet on the ground with more money than he could earn. Did that wallet have more money than he could make in a day? A week? A year? WE DON’T KNOW AND WHO CARES. Stop asking so many questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;master-xi-is-a-really-dope-name-to-be-honest&quot;&gt;Master Xi is a really dope name, to be honest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s important here is that Noel was honest and gave the wallet back to the owner, who happened to be Master Xi. That’s when Master Xi rewarded Noel by giving him the Feng Shui Black Obsidian bracelet. Immediately from here on out, Noel’s life totally changed. And even many other people told Noel that the bracelet changed their life too. It also healed their illness. What illness? Again, WHO CARES, this thing is covered in gold and Obsidian. Keep your eye on the blinking bar and read the text. This isn’t a Q&amp;amp;A session. Noel is here to teach you how to cure whatever the fuck you got. It even provided more work opportunities for some and generally made people feel more confident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if you’ve realized yet, but this bracelet is fucking amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;einstein-would-totally-wear-the-feng-shui-bracelet&quot;&gt;Einstein would totally wear the Feng Shui bracelet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still skeptical? Noel goes on to implore you to recognize the importance of the energy in and around us. He quotes Einstein’s famous equation E = mc&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; to remind us that matter is tightly related to energy. Energy shapes matter, so if we can shape our energy, we can begin to shape our future. That’s right, the bracelet is backed up by SCIENCE. Einstein said it himself. You gonna sit there with your broke ass calling Einstein stupid? Why shape your energy with a healthy diet and exercise when all you really need is to carry around some Feng Shui on your wrist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noel isn’t a lowly garbage collector anymore. Now he works closely with Master Xi to bring these bracelets to the world. Which may sound like he got roped into a multi-level marketing scheme if you’re the type of hater that keeps pointy things on their desk. Thankfully the Obsidian blocks out all that hater energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-feel-richer-simply-by-looking-at-the-bracelet&quot;&gt;I feel richer simply by looking at the bracelet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we reach the end of the video, and all you have to do is click the link and wait for your Feng Shui black Obsidian bracelet. What a fantastic journey of transformation we were able to make in three minutes and thirty-eight seconds. For only $20 you, and everyone else, can have access to all the wealth, health, and prosperity you dreamed of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">Do you want to learn more about Feng Shui and how to use it to shake $20 from people’s pockets? Well, I have the deal of a lifetime for you. Reading this blog post is going to unlock real wealth and happiness in your life. Not that fake knock of wealth and happiness. So let’s learn more about Feng Shui and how you can attain everything you’ve ever wanted.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oh My Gosh turn your PWA into an Android app in the Google play store</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh My Gosh turn your PWA into an Android app in the Google play store" /><published>2020-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa/">&lt;p&gt;Do you have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_web_application&quot;&gt;Progressive Web App (PWA)&lt;/a&gt; that you would love to see in Google’s Android play store? You can make that happen today! With &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChromeLabs/bubblewrap&quot;&gt;bubblewrap from GoogleChromeLabs&lt;/a&gt;. It is an experimental tool that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChromeLabs/bubblewrap/tree/master/packages/cli&quot;&gt;uses a CLI&lt;/a&gt; to process your PWA and generate an apk you can upload to the play store. Let’s look at how I did it for one of my sites. Now, mrpowerscripts.com isn’t a PWA… yet. But I have many other flat Jekyll sites that are progressive web apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progressive-web-apps-look-like-native-apps&quot;&gt;Progressive Web apps look like native apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You install a progressive web app through browsers like Chome. Not every browser supports PWAs yet, but support is growing. For instance, Firefox Mobile supports them, but Firefox Desktop, as of this date, does not. All you need to do to turn your website into a progressive web app is to add a manifest file with the details of your PWA and a service worker. Here is an example of my manifest.json file, which lives in the root of my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;ThisIsMySiteOrPWAName&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;short_name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;ThisIsShorter&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;theme_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;#39a4cd&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;background_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;#fff&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;prefer_related_applications&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;display&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;standalone&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;Scope&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;start_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/?utm_source=a2hs&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;icons&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;src&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;assets/img/favicon/manifest-icon-192.png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;sizes&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;192x192&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;image/png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;src&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;assets/img/favicon/manifest-icon-512.png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;sizes&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;512x512&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;image/png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browsers will see this file and know that it should treat your site as a progressive web app. You also need to configure a service worker, which allows your PWA to have cool capabilities. Like offline viewing with caching, and push notifications. You know, like a native app! But this isn’t a howto on setting up a PWA. I’m assuming you already have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bubblewrap-cli&quot;&gt;The bubblewrap CLI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a site that is working as a PWA, you can start using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChromeLabs/bubblewrap/tree/master/packages/cli&quot;&gt;the bubblewrap CLI&lt;/a&gt;. Now, this may feel a bit overwhelming but stay with me here. Here are the commands you need to run to turn the PWA into an APK. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bubblewrap init --manifest https://example.com/manifest.json&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bubblewrap build&lt;/code&gt;. That’s it? That’s it. The bubblewrap CLI tool pulls in your PWA manifest file information and uses it to initialize the project. It might be a good idea to use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--directory=&lt;/code&gt; on the init as well, so it keeps everything in a folder for you. Then you can turn that folder into a git repo and track the changes. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bubblewrap build&lt;/code&gt; command takes the initialized project and uses it to build an Android APK. From there, you can treat it as a standard Android APK file. Like uploading it to the play store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you went to look at the repo, you’ll notice that there is a bit of setup because of dependencies. But it seems like this is a relatively new project that has a lot of ongoing work, so I think the dependencies will be managed better in the future. The great thing is that it works now! If you have any issues setting it up pop into &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/mrps-discord&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; and get help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-works-thanks-to-trusted-web-activity&quot;&gt;This works thanks to Trusted Web Activity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trusted web activity is an open way to verify trusted web content within an Android app. So, anything that is being opened by the mobile Chrome browser within an app. Sometimes you’ll see native apps can load web content in a browser. It’s still chrome, but apps use this feature of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/android/custom-tabs/implementation-guide&quot;&gt;Chrome Browser called Custom Tabs&lt;/a&gt;. This lets app developers make their apps open content in a browser without having to build a mobile browser themselves. It’s very convenient, and our generated APK file basically opens our PWA right into a Chrome Custom Tab instance. Then TWA tells the browser that the content is from the same developer as the app. How does the browser know that the website it’s opening is a TWA? It does this by creating a Digital Asset Links file, which like the manifest file, is accessible from your website. It would live here: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://example.com/.well-known/assetlinks.json&lt;/code&gt; Here’s an example &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;assetlinks.json&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/android/trusted-web-activity/quick-start#creating-your-asset-link-file&quot;&gt;Google’s TWA Quickstart guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;relation&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;delegate_permission/common.handle_all_urls&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;target&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;namespace&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;android_app&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;package_name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;com.appspot.pwa_directory&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;sha256_cert_fingerprints&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;FA:2A:03:CB:38:9C:F3:BE:28:E3:CA:7F:DA:2E:FA:4F:4A:96:F3:BC:45:2C:08:A2:16:A1:5D:FD:AB:46:BC:9D&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;4F:FF:49:FF:C6:1A:22:E3:BB:6F:E6:E1:E6:5B:40:17:55:C0:A9:F9:02:D9:BF:28:38:0B:AE:A7:46:A0:61:8C&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created that file through a tool in their quickstart guide called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Peter's Asset Link Tool&lt;/code&gt;. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=dev.conn.assetlinkstool&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;download Peter’s Asset Link Tool&lt;/a&gt; from the Play store. After publishing a Beta version of the app to the play store and downloading it, I was able to use that tool to generate the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;assetlinks.json&lt;/code&gt; file and add it to my site. So when the generated APK opens my PWA using Chrome, it knows that I made the app because of the fingerprint on my website. My content is therefor trusted and granted special abilities like being full screen in the custom tab. Otherwise, you would see the chrome toolbar at the top. Similar to when you see other native apps open a custom tab browser. So it’s a website disguised as a PWA disguised as a native app. It’s pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWA’s brought a lot of power to websites on native devices, and TWA with fancy new tools is further blurring the line between web and native applications. In this case, I only need one code base and my responsive site works on Desktop, tablets, mobile devices, Play store, and many more interfaces thanks to simple web conventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it out!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">Do you have a Progressive Web App (PWA) that you would love to see in Google’s Android play store? You can make that happen today! With bubblewrap from GoogleChromeLabs. It is an experimental tool that uses a CLI to process your PWA and generate an apk you can upload to the play store. Let’s look at how I did it for one of my sites. Now, mrpowerscripts.com isn’t a PWA… yet. But I have many other flat Jekyll sites that are progressive web apps.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">U need 2 Iterate. You need to iterate. Iteration is necessary.</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="U need 2 Iterate. You need to iterate. Iteration is necessary." /><published>2020-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration/">&lt;p&gt;So I posted the &lt;a href=&quot;/best-blog-post-ever/&quot;&gt;best blog post ever&lt;/a&gt; the other day. And it challenged anyone who disagreed with the notion that it’s the best blog post to tell me why so that I could make it better. Now the point was to highlight two critical components to successful growth more so than profess that it’s the best blog post ever. I mean, is it REALLY the best blog post ever? Yes, obviously. It says so in the title, why wouldn’t it be true? But that isn’t the point of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that growth comes from iteration and feedback. And you need to keep doing that over and over again. When do you stop? Never. Unless you’ve built a video game about digging digital dirt blocks and sold it for 4 billion dollars. At that point, you’ve won the game. You can stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more often you iterate on some “thing,” and the more you analyze the results of that iteration and use it to guide future iterations, the better your future results could be. Oh my gosh, doesn’t that sound like machine learning? Oh my gosh, guess what? You’re a machine too! A squishy fleshy machine that may or may not enjoy watching SpongeBob Squarepants because that’s easier than failing over and over again. Computers don’t have an ego, so they’re a bit more open to the criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s simply part of the iteration process. Fucking up a lot is a great way to find out what works best and what doesn’t. Every single time you identify a crosswalk or a bus in those Google ReCaptchas, you’re essentially judging a machine at how well it was able to guess the object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“oh, hello, random human. Look at all these traffic light pictures I’ve selected for you! aren’t they wonderful?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then you correct the little machine robot tried its best, and Google uses that feedback to build a more reliable robot. Wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what machine? It’s the same for you. Want to get good at something. Start doing it. Try. Fail a lot. Keep trying. Learn from those mistakes. In the pursuit of perfection &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/quantity-always-trumps-quality/&quot;&gt;quantity always trumps quality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to be a great artist? Start drawing. Now. Find places you can share it online. Listen to that criticism. You don’t have to agree or accept everything. And that’s part of the challenge with feedback. Not all of it is good. But if you can learn how to dig through the feedback mountain, you learn to find the gems from it.  I still struggle with this a lot, but I know it’s the truth. Not everything is as simple as identifying a bus or a car in a picture. But with enough iterations, you’ll develop your intuitions, and those will help you figure out what sort of feedback can add or subtract value. Oh my goodness, the process of iteration and feedback loops works on learning how to receive feedback as well??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think this idea of developing quick iteration and feedback loops is critical for successful growth across pretty much everything. If you’re a software company that can push updates and then receives feedback quickly from users - guess what? You’re going to develop much better software a lot faster than companies who can’t. Another thought - guess who is going to have a better jump shot? Someone who practices every day or practices once a week? Practice makes perfect isn’t a new concept. It’s been around long before any of us have bee been born. I’m going to throw three bits of info that I think is super important for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write shit down. Analyze yourself. Go back and read old things you wrote. Old songs you sang, pictures you drew, software you programmed, workout tapes you recorded. You get the picture. Can you spot things you can improve? Can you build a better version of your past works? Test yourself often. Stay sharp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find people who share your growth interests. I have people from all kinds of backgrounds who I regularly contact for feedback, and when they come to me, I provide the same assistance. One of the areas I reach out to friends about is design. I’m a terrible designer, but I’m worlds ahead of where I was years ago. Thanks to the time they shared with me providing critical feedback in their area of expertise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build your intuitions. When you’ve iterated enough on something, your brain will develop shortcuts. It can happen with hobbies, career skills, whatever. You won’t have to think as much to perform them efficiently. You will find yourself in a &lt;a href=&quot;/mindfulness-meditation-flow/&quot;&gt;state of flow&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to jump in and complete tasks without wasted effort. That is where you want to find yourself, and you do it through iterating and analyzing those results to improve the next attempt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn a lot from yourself and others, but when you begin feeling confident in taking action, that’s when the real fun begins. But to get there, and achieve excellent results, sometimes it takes a bit of luck. But even luck can’t save you if you don’t try.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">So I posted the best blog post ever the other day. And it challenged anyone who disagreed with the notion that it’s the best blog post to tell me why so that I could make it better. Now the point was to highlight two critical components to successful growth more so than profess that it’s the best blog post ever. I mean, is it REALLY the best blog post ever? Yes, obviously. It says so in the title, why wouldn’t it be true? But that isn’t the point of it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This is the best blog post ever</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/best-blog-post-ever/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is the best blog post ever" /><published>2020-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/best-blog-post-ever</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/best-blog-post-ever/">&lt;p&gt;Do you disagree? Okay, I know you haven’t read it yet, but you probably had some preconceived idea that it wasn’t - didn’t you? A small bit of bias? None? You didn’t even weigh the possibility a bit? Well, if you don’t think it is - Why not? What doesn’t it have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, here’s the thing about this blog post. It isn’t afraid of change. It’s a living document. It &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/MrPowerScripts.com/blob/master/_posts/2020-03-22-best-blog-post-ever.md&quot;&gt;lives here in GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, where it is committed to being the best blog post ever. So if it isn’t, tell me why. You can do it here on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/mrps-discord&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/MrPowerScripts.com/issues&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MrPowerScripts&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or even by &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:playingwithpowershell@gmail.com&quot;&gt;e-mail&lt;/a&gt;. This blog post can take on the challenge. This blog post isn’t afraid to be the best. This blog post IS the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="automation" /><summary type="html">Do you disagree? Okay, I know you haven’t read it yet, but you probably had some preconceived idea that it wasn’t - didn’t you? A small bit of bias? None? You didn’t even weigh the possibility a bit? Well, if you don’t think it is - Why not? What doesn’t it have?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Automate Simple Static Website Testing</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/automate-static-site-testing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automate Simple Static Website Testing" /><published>2020-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/automate-static-site-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/automate-static-site-testing/">&lt;p&gt;I like using Jekyll to build static websites when I can. A static website is a site built with simple HTML, CSS, and Javascript. Ready to be served up by webservers. Jekyll is one of the many frameworks that help create static websites by using nifty features like templating, and an embedded development server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These static site generators can’t prevent you from writing bad structure to your HTML other potential problems. You can have borked syntax or bad links throughout the generated website source code that may go undeteceted. Even JSON files can also be generated with invalid syntax very easily. And there’s plenty of tools to help you avoid shipping that crappy code live. Plus…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALL. OF. THIS. CAN. BE. AUTOMATED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YAY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to use a few tools that other people have written, and that’s the easiest part about this whole thing. First thing is test all of the JSON files that my site generates using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jsonlint&lt;/code&gt; combined with a command that finds all of the JSON files in the site directory tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;FILES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;find ./_site &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-type&lt;/span&gt; f &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'*.json'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$FILES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; jsonlint &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$FILES&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code above uses the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;find&lt;/code&gt; command to locate all the JSON files in the directory, and displays them on the screen, and then passes them to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jsonlint&lt;/code&gt;, which will validate that all of the files are good whomesome JSON like Mom used to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great. So now we know our JSON isn’t screwed up. We can make sure that all of the site HTML is well-formed as well. We’ll use a tool called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;htmlproofer&lt;/code&gt; which can check the integrity of the produced site. You can see everything it tests &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gjtorikian/html-proofer&quot;&gt;here on their repo&lt;/a&gt;. I run the command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;htmlproofer ./_site &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--check-html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--disable-external&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--check-opengraph&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--check-favicon&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I tried &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;htmlproofer&lt;/code&gt; on one of my Jekyll sites, it found over 300 errors. It took me a while to fix all of the broken issues with my HTML, but &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;htmlproofer&lt;/code&gt; helped me test it very quickly as I was updating the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, this isn’t really testing, but sometimes allowing the wrong sizes of images to get through can provide a poor user experience. So why not automate preventing that? We can do that with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mogrify&lt;/code&gt; command from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://imagemagick.org/script/download.php&quot;&gt;ImageMagick toolset&lt;/a&gt;. I use the command below on one of my sites to make sure images are no larger than 500px on either side, and this will resize them if they are, which helps make sure image file sizes are smaller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;find ./_site/assets/img/ &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'*.jpg'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-execdir&lt;/span&gt; mogrify &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-resize&lt;/span&gt; 500x &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes that isn’t enough to get the file sizes down to a reasonable level. We can use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jpegoptim&lt;/code&gt; command to enforce that image files are under a specific file size, and automatically optimize the image to fit within that limit. The command below grabs all image files in a folder and reduces their sizes to below 70k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;find ./_site/assets/img &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-type&lt;/span&gt; d &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-exec&lt;/span&gt; sh &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'ls &quot;$0&quot;/*.jpg 2&amp;gt;/dev/null &amp;amp;&amp;amp; jpegoptim --size=70k --max=90 --all-progressive --strip-all -t &quot;$0&quot;/*.jpg'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you can automate all of that using devops tools like CircleCI for testing and trimming your source before it gets deployed somewhere, like GitHub pages, which is where this blog lives. Every commit I push to update the website automatically gets validated through CircleCI using the tools above. The CircleCI config with test and deploy jobs make sure the site is validated every single time I make a change before it gets deployed live — no more shipping sites with tons of broken code that can hurt SEO or the user’s experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;http://gist-it.appspot.com/http://github.com/MrPowerScripts/MrPowerScripts.com/blob/master/.circleci/config.yml&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I pushed the change that contained this blog post &lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/gh/MrPowerScripts/MrPowerScripts.com/298&quot;&gt;it actually hit an error&lt;/a&gt; because I added a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; where it can break site formatting. The CircleCI job failed and the site was not deployed. I was able to fix the site code and &lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/workflow-run/852b83a1-84ec-425a-823b-c5032b288265&quot;&gt;push a new commit&lt;/a&gt; where it was validated as successful and the site was deployed successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could take the website optimization a few steps further by using tools that help minimize the site source code or run SEO checks. But using these simple tools drastically improved the confidence of the code I was shipping out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="automation" /><summary type="html">I like using Jekyll to build static websites when I can. A static website is a site built with simple HTML, CSS, and Javascript. Ready to be served up by webservers. Jekyll is one of the many frameworks that help create static websites by using nifty features like templating, and an embedded development server.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I orgaize my life with apps</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/calendar-contacts-tasks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I orgaize my life with apps" /><published>2020-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/calendar-contacts-tasks</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/calendar-contacts-tasks/">&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of stuff. Like, I should probably chill out a bit, but I can’t. I have a lot of passions, and they keep me super busy. I work an (almost) full-time job at a tech startup for the moment. Anyone that has worked for a startup knows that there’s an endless amount of work that needs to be done and usually not enough people to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I’ve been there for a couple of years. I know how to do my job reasonably efficiently. But I also have my side projects. This blog, the youtube channel that goes with it, (okay I haven’t updated either of them in a long time - but I think about them! does that count?). I have some other websites that I work on, which i’m trying to grow, and I have people helping with them. I manage and run a bunch of performance related events in the city where I live, which takes quite a bit of time coordinating with venues and performers. Plus other hobbies like playing basketball, video games, working on short films, helping friends with their projects. On top of all the essentials - laundry, making meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m always so. fuckin. busy. The honest solution is that I should chill out a bit and drop some of these things. But I’m way too stubborn to do that. So, I have to use simple tricks that help me keep o top of everything. And that’s the key for me. The methods I use are SIMPLE. A complicated system of organization only adds to the chaos for me. So everything I’m about to list most likely won’t blow anyone away, but they truly help me out a lot in keeping track of what I need to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HERE IS THE (short) LIST OF SIMPLE TRICKS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Calendar. I use Google calendar. If it’s not on the calendar - it doesn’t matter. I don’t put frivolous things on my calendar. I don’t need a reminder to feed the cat every day. The cat does that just fine. When I wake up, I look at the calendar widget on the home screen of my phone. It tells me everything I NEED to be concerned with that day. But I also look at the coming days to help decide how I should spend currently available free time, and having few items as possible makes it easier to do that. Some people might feel the need to “block off that time for everything”. No thanks. I don’t want a cluttered calendar with my entire day planned out to the minute. I want as few things on the schedule as possible. My key to success here is to be aware of what is coming up and utilize the free spaces effectively in the moments they become available. When my calendar is lean, it’s easier to see what is coming up today, tomorrow, and the next day. And it allows me the flexibility to manage my free time in the moment, which includes preparing for things coming up in the near term. Some people enjoy micromanaging their time, but I prefer to spend as little time in the calendar app as possible. With a quick swipe, I can see a couple of days of things that are important for me to be aware of, and I decide when/how to prepare for those events in the gaps between them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whatsapp. I use WhatsApp as my primary means of communication. As pretty much everyone else does in Europe. But I use it more or less as a task list for things related to other people. You can very easily archive conversations, so I use that feature often. If I’m done communicating with someone, and there’s no follow up needed - the conversation gets archived. So my conversation list is very often empty when I open the app. I often see people with a gigantic list of conversations, and because of my system, it drives me bonkers. If I need to reply to a person about something, if I need to follow up with them in any way - the conversation stays open. Otherwise, everyone gets archived.  So I treat Whatsapp as a task list for other people primarily. Sometimes I’ll have a name there for a couple of days if there’s a long-running follow-up. It happens. But making this a habit allows me to focus better and not drop the ball on doing things for other people. Again, it also keeps reminders and events off my calendar. That’s a place for things that most concern me. Whatsapp is a task list for matters related to other people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An actual “to-do list”. I use an app with a widget on my phone’s home screen that’s called “to-do list”. Amazing - I know. The to-do list is where I put things that aren’t time-sensitive like small side projects I would like to create or ideas I should look into when I have some free time. Something that I can follow up on in those moments between calendar items. And when they get done - I check quickly knock them off the list. It could be a blog post idea or a video idea.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are a few basic techniques I use to stay on top of things for myself and others. I may have other things I’m not thinking of at the moment. But if I think of anything else I’ll add it to my to-do list and be sure to update this blog post in the future when I have some free time :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">I do a lot of stuff. Like, I should probably chill out a bit, but I can’t. I have a lot of passions, and they keep me super busy. I work an (almost) full-time job at a tech startup for the moment. Anyone that has worked for a startup knows that there’s an endless amount of work that needs to be done and usually not enough people to do it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advanced function parameters in Powershell</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/advanced-function-parameters-in-powershell/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced function parameters in Powershell" /><published>2019-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/advanced-function-parameters-in-powershell</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/advanced-function-parameters-in-powershell/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re not making use of functions in your Powershell code then you need to stop what you’re doing right now and learn about them! But where?!? Oh, click the video below and watch. That will get you started. &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;qz0x_WL8ueo&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s awesome! Now you know what functions are! Exciting! But after you’ve made a function you’ll probably want to adapt it a bit. Reusability of code without some customization is super limiting. Next you’ll want to learn how to add parameters to your functions. By adding parameters to your functions you’ll unlock the true power of functions in Powershell! Thankfully the video below will get you up to speed on function parameters in powershell. Then you’re ready for the advanced stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;RW2tRebxqzQ&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now you know what functions are in Powershell, and you’ve learned a few ways to add parameters to them. But if you create your Powershell functions without some of the advanced Powershell function parameter techniques you might be setting yourself up for future disaster! Leading you or others using your code to end up in an endless pit of darkness and dispair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few reasons why you would want to use advanced powershell function parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Control the types of arguments passed into functions. If someone puts an string into a function when it should be an integer Powershell will automatically warn them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flags allow you to modify a powershell functions behavior without users needing to supply a parameter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create help messages for your parameters so that users will know how to use them appropriately&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure some parameters to be mandatory and prevent the function from running if it is unused&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add validation to the arguments passed into the function. Only want the user to enter a number between 1 and 100? You can enforce that. Do you want to control whether they can pass in a null value, or empty string? You can validate for that as well. You can even validate the argument using a regex string.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Control whether or not an argument can be passed into the function through the powershell Pipleline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a few of the benefits, and there are even more! Adding some of these advanced powershell function parameter techniques can seriously improve the reliablity and reusability of your functions. Check out the video below to see some of the benefits in action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;6ySxsnOGnCU&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><category term="powershell function parameters" /><category term="advanced powershellfunction parameters" /><category term="functions in powershell" /><category term="powershell functions." /><summary type="html">If you’re not making use of functions in your Powershell code then you need to stop what you’re doing right now and learn about them! But where?!? Oh, click the video below and watch. That will get you started. That’s awesome! Now you know what functions are! Exciting! But after you’ve made a function you’ll probably want to adapt it a bit. Reusability of code without some customization is super limiting. Next you’ll want to learn how to add parameters to your functions. By adding parameters to your functions you’ll unlock the true power of functions in Powershell! Thankfully the video below will get you up to speed on function parameters in powershell. Then you’re ready for the advanced stuff!</summary></entry></feed>