<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>MrPowerScripts</title>
		<description>Learn. Code. Grow.</description>		
		<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com</link>
		<atom:link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Send GET requests to API with Powershell</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;When I started learning Powershell web technologies were mostly a mystery for me. I was a simple systems admin trying to make my life easier by automating things. Sure, I knew how to create a basic HTML site with some CSS, but even javascript was well beyond my understanding. Though over time I developed an interest in developing for the web, which spurred me to learn how Powershell can interact with things beyond my computer or local network. &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;7mEmQgGowMY&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I scrape a website with Powershell? How can I access an API? How can I send data from my computer to services on the web? I had so many questions for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;9piyM38it_8&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered the concept of an API and found it absolutely amazing. Having a standard way for different computers with different operating systems running different programs build with different code sounded so cool. I don’t need a browser to interact with this website? That’s amazing! Think of all the automation possibilities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I found out about RESTful or a REST API design. Through the process of learning about REST APIs, I discovered the JSON data format. As someone who had to work a lot with verbose XML files for configuration data and data transfer, it looked like an amazing alternative.  Once I learned a bit more about what a REST API is and how to format data as JSON it opened up this new world of communicating with other systems through the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to use Invoke-WebRequest in Powershell to GET or POST data from various API resources. I looked around for all kinds of APIs on the internet to see what I could do with them. That encouraged me to learn how to make my own API interfaces. Which I eventually managed to do using tools like Flask with Python and ExpressJS with NodeJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Powershell cmdlet Invoke-WebRequest automatically turned JSON objects from GET requests into Powershell Objects which made it super easy to inspect and play around with the data from the command line. Making it super easy to test and play around with the data I was passing through the APIs I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, request tools like Postman and Insomnia became popular, and I generally steered away from using Windows while developing. When all of my web work started though Powershell was there to help me along, and I still think it’s a really great tool for quickly scripting and working with data at the command line. Objects are awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve linked above the two videos I made about using Invoke-WebRequest to make Get and Post requests. Those two are all you need to get started with the fun world of APIs and web automation with Powershell. Happy scripting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/rest-api-powershell/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/rest-api-powershell/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Automate Installing IP Printers With Powershell</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite ways of saving time as a systems administrator was automating the installation of printers. You don’t need Powershell for it. I often times did with simple batch scripts. PowerShell is all the rage in the world of Windows these days, so that’s why the video examples use it. &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;E2x6NG72tn4&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning how to automate printer installations really saved me a lot of time in previous jobs, but it wasn’t always easy changing a culture of manual effort. Sometimes you have to wait for the right opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was working at a commercial bank as a customer support slash junior systems admin for the company. Their support team didn’t automate anything. I had previously come from work cultures where we did our very best to automate ourselves out of a job. It was frustrating, but I saw an awesome opportunity to make the lives of my team easier and improve the support experience. There was one problem with my plan. Nobody wanted to change their ways. Wait, what? This is CLEARLY a better way of doing things? How could they not embrace this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to let it go for a long time. We continued to manually VNC into peoples computers if they needed a printer to be (re)installed. I hated it. so. much. The tides turned when a big office project came into focus. We needed to rename all of the network printer names and IP addresse for all the printers in the office. Two giant floors of people needed all the printers on their computers updated to use the new naming conventions. We were instructed to do this by hand for each user in the office as the printer names and IP addresses were updated. There were so many frustrating questions that ran through my head which had no great answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the hell are we supposed to know which users will be impacted by the change? There was no way to tell who had what installed on their machines. We were supposed to make assumptions. How long is it going to take to update each person’s machine? Some people had four or five printers installed. I would have to go back and forth referencing a document to install the printers for every single person. That is a significant disruption in the users workday, and collectively, a huge pain in the ass for me and my team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the first-day interrupting people before I decided to write up a script that would do all this work for us. I initially received a lot of pushback against it. A senior colleague on the team instructed me not to use it when I showed him because it hadn’t been approved by management. So, I went to our manager. He was also initially against the idea. He said no when I showed him what it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so upset. I went back to my desk dejected getting ready to interrupt more peoples day. “uh, how long is this going to take?”. “Can you do it after I leave?”. No, I want to get out of here at 5 pm as well Brad. I guess our manager saw the light in the end. I’m not sure what changed his mind but he later came to me and asked if I thought it was ready to be used in live action. Hell yeah, it’s automation time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script was simple. We had an excel document that had the old computer names and their new name/IP combo. I took that data and embedded it within a PowerShell script. When you ran the script it would check to see if you had any of the old names on your computer. If it found an old name it would uninstall it and then install the corresponding new name/IP. Combined with a batch script sitting on a file server it was possible to click a link in an email to run the script and update all of the computers on that computer. It generated a little report on the computer so we could inspect what happened if someone reported issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This changed the whole game. This was a project that was expected to take over a week. It would have taken many hours of productivity away from our team and others in the company. In the end, we were able to send out an email with a link to click and users could attempt the conversion at their convenience. How beautiful is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t the first time I tried to change “how we do things here”, but it was one of the most satisfying. I was given significant freedom to script solutions to daily problems after that. People would come to me asking if scripting some problem was possible. It encouraged others on the team to take some classes on PowerShell, and think differently about how we solve problems in the office. Watching the culture change was wonderful. I enjoyed working there a lot more after that. It might not always be the right time to change things, but you can always keep your eyes open for those opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/automate-install-ip-printer-with-powershell/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/automate-install-ip-printer-with-powershell/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Continuous Integration Meme Delivery With CircleCI</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I made a video about continuous integration and continuous delivery. Also known as CI/CD. The cool way to do DevOps! Are you not practicing this yet? I bet you’re still writing checks. You probably still think dippin’ dots are the future of ice cream. At least the future of software development is here, so dive in old timer. We write tests now and YOLO every commit out to production faster than anyone has time to review them. &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;oHaYyZgiDIU&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writing tests part is optional for maximum YOLO. You won’t see this being taught in school, but I also like to dab at my desk every time I push a commit. Let all the haters (colleagues) know that I’m making some changes around here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working very closely in the CI/CD space for more than a year now. I’ve found that the practice really aligns with how I prefer to build out my own projects. If you’ve completed a feature, fixed a bug, or improved the look of your application why not get those changes out to your users as soon as possible? I want to see the stuff I’ve created go live and so do the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, instead of making a practical example I chose to do something completely unnecessary and ridiculous to share this lovely concept of CI/CD. I configured a repository to deploy memes with CircleCI. The general idea is that you can keep your memes in git version control, and when you want to deploy a meme CircleCI will automate the workflow. I even added some tests to make sure the image isn’t too large or too small. Remember, tests are completely optional and reduce your YOLO score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment it automates deploying the meme to Reddit after it uploads it to Imgur. The memes can be managed in their own branches, and when you want to release a meme to Reddit you simply create and push a git tag. How pointless and cool is that? It’s easier than ever to pollute the internet with memes nobody will ever care about. You’re welcome society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/meme-cd&quot;&gt;find the code here on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; if you want to deploy your own memes to Reddit. Deploy memes faster than anyone else on the planet using continuous meme delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/continuous-meme-delivery/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/continuous-meme-delivery/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sending an email from Powershell using send-mailmessage and Gmail</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I made this video about sending an email from Powershell about five years ago. I didn’t think much of it at the time, but I used my actual email address in the example of the video. This resulted in people copy/pasting the example including my email and sending me all of their test emails. I’ve really loved it! &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;gxHdAic6im8&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script below will show how to use send-mailmessage with Gmail to send emails from Powershell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never think that something as simple as sending an email from Powershell could be interesting to so many people. I didn’t think so at the time. Since that video has existed I’ve received “test” emails from people all over the world working at lots of different companies. Big and small. Governments and non-profits. It’s hard to imagine how sharing something so simple can impact so many people. If you want to bug me as well here’s the code itself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$MyEmail = &quot;PlayingWithPowershell@gmail.com&quot;
$SMTP= &quot;smtp.gmail.com&quot;
$To = &quot;PlayingWithPowershell@gmail.com&quot;
$Subject = &quot;BRO!&quot;
$Body = &quot;WHAT UP MR.POWERSCRIPTS?&quot;
$Creds = (Get-Credential -Credential &quot;$MyEmail&quot;)

Start-Sleep 2

Send-MailMessage -To $to -From $MyEmail -Subject $Subject -Body $Body -SmtpServer $SMTP -Credential $Creds -UseSsl -Port 587 -DeliveryNotificationOption never

&amp;lt;#
$PSEmailServer variable can be used to pre-configure the
SMTP server in your Powershell Profile. Then you don't need
to specify -smtpserver paramter. Send-MailMessage will use the
SMTP sever address assigned to $PSEmailServer
Delivery Notification Options:
-- None: No notification.
-- OnSuccess: Notify if the delivery is successful.
-- OnFailure: Notify if the delivery is unsuccessful.
-- Delay: Notify if the delivery is delayed.
-- Never: Never notify.
#&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://myaccount.google.com/security&quot;&gt;https://myaccount.google.com/security&lt;/a&gt; and scroll all the way to the bottom to toggle on “Allow less secure apps” if you want to try this with your Gmail account like in the video example. You can toggle it back off once you’ve finished screwing around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll usually reply when I have time. With something like “Congratulations! It Worked!”. 99% of the time I never hear a reply back. But once in a while, I’ll get further requests for support. Which I don’t reply to 99% of the time. Ya’ll know how to use Google like I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/sending-an-email-from-powershell/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/sending-an-email-from-powershell/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>That time I destroyed a customer's computer</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This was a very different video than I’m used to making! I’m pretty sure this is the first storytelling video I’ve made for the channel. Sharing a not so spectacular experience from early on in my IT career. &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;hHMKyfGkiNY&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to wipe a customer’s entire hard drive, and that was a pretty grim week for me. But shit happens. We learn and move on. I’m well aware the video is corny as hell with the background audio. I like corn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’m going to think about making more videos like this. I’ve been in the game for almost fifteen years at this point. There’s been many highs and lows. If someone can learn or laugh at those experiences it’s worth sharing. We’ll see. I haven’t had a lot of time for making videos lately, so I need to figure out how to streamline my creation process if I want to get anything out at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/whoops-sorry-customer/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/whoops-sorry-customer/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The best nodejs version manager - n</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Nodejs is the javascript runtime that will not go away even though &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2709539&quot;&gt;people have been complaining about it for a long time&lt;/a&gt;. Things get trickier when you add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt; into the mix. Your project you want to work on might require an older version of nodejs, but you have the latest and greatest version installed. &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;bsJj6ii9_Fk&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incredibly simple tool with a fitting name called - n - can help you quickly manage the version of node that you’re currently using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions to install n &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tj/n&quot;&gt;can be found right on their GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;. The docs are really great, so I don’t think they need repeating here. There are of course other node version managers but I’ve found n to do everything I need. I can change the version of node with a quick and short command. If the version I want isn’t installed it will install it for me before switching to that version. What more could you ask for when all you need is a nodejs version manager? Definitely check it out if you’re looking for something simple.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/best-nodejs-manager/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/best-nodejs-manager/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How I got a job with a ridiculous opening email.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago my then girlfriend wanted to find a better job. I had a lot more experience going on interviews and generally traversing the drudgery of job searching so I helped her through the process. She found a job posting that interested her but wasn’t within the umbrella of her education or previous work experience. I jokingly commented that I could probably get the job before she did, and this ended up turning into a competition. I had no relevant education or work experience in this field either, but I’m a great bullshitter so I gave it my best shot. We both applied for the job with our own unique approaches. The job title was &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Junior Amazing And Talented Content Creator&lt;/code&gt;. The following is the email I sent them. All grammar and spelling mistakes included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I found your advertisement for someone to help create content and drive traffic for an editorial calendar - or something. It was a rather poorly written advertisement, and I see that you seriously need some help. Also, a number of the requirements were listed multiple times. Now, had the font been adjusted to comic sans on the second appearance I could have assumed you were intentionally duplicating the entries for emphasis. Since the overall quality of the advert was hovering somewhere around poor to abysmal I feel it’s safe to assume negligence was the root cause here.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You need help. Let me help you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I’ll give you a really short background that I think can help emphasize why I really embody many of the requirements you’re looking for. I come from a very poor background. When I was young my parents struggled to supply me with a lot the essentials for life. Sure they managed to put a roof over my head, and there was food on the table. But there’s a lot of other things that can really propel you to success when you have them at a young age. I learned this lesson early on in life.
You see while my family was borderline destitute, we lived in a rather wealthy area. Rich people need someone to clean their clothes and fix their cars right? Well, that’s exactly what my parents did. My father was a mechanic and my mother was a domestic worker. Immigrants to a foreign country doing their best to provide their children an opportunity to be successful. Their best they did, though going to school mixed among the privileged children helped to carve a deep understanding of class divides in a way only have-nots can truly appreciate. Now it was apparent to my precocious mind that there’s many indicators which show individuals are on either side of the divide. For instance, buying new clothes and outfits seasonally. Stories of family vacations to foreign countries. Separate rooms for cooking and bathing at home. Out of all the differences though the one,that stuck out for me the most was a sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It was clear to see that a sense of humor was afforded to the privileged class. I would have traded all of my new clothes, foreign vacations, or task specific rooms in my home if it meant I could have my very own sense of humor. Since I didn’t even those I knew it would take other means to acquire what I desired most. Trading for what you wanted was a means for the lower classes anyway. No more so on display than lunch time at school sitting at the table with my underprivileged friends. We spent most of the time bartering with one other in hopes to receive edibles that we actually wanted to consume. Tensions often rising as heated debates over peanut-butter sandwiches for cheese and toast turned friends to enemies. God forbid someone realized the capri-sun they had traded for was a re-labeled knock off and the whole table need prepare for a meltdown. That was never the case for the rich kids table. They all had what they wanted and spent lunch time eating and laughing. Their parents had packed in a sense of humor with their lunchables and freshly squeezed juices to be enjoyed all throughout the day. It hurt to see others have so much that it allowed them to spend their time differently, and obviously more enjoyably.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I knew that my parents worked hard for the little we had and so I never really bothered them for big purchases. Though one year as Christmas time was rolling around I thought it might be the perfect opportunity to try and ask for something big. Just this one time I hoped. I’ll never forget the day. I walked up to my father while he was reading his newspaper. I still remember my body trembling as I licked my lips and uttered, “Papa, do you think for this Christmas you could get me a sense of humor?”. He let a huge sigh while folding up his newspaper and shaking his head. Even as the breadwinner for the household it was something he himself was unable to afford. Which may be why he took the folded up newspaper and slapped me across the face while telling me to go bother my Mother. I never gave up though. From that moment on I knew that if I wanted a sense a humor I was going to have to buy it myself.
From that point on I spent years working hard to save up any bit of money I could. I mowed lawns and shoveled snow. I picked up pennies from the ground and put everything into my little bank.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It was finally in my late teens that I dared make another attempt at procuring what I had always desired. Having finally saved up a notable sum of money for someone at that age I felt safe in confiding to a friend my intentions. Even with him, someone I had trusted even more than my family, the challenges arose once again. “You can’t buy a sense of humor”, he explained. “What?!”, I responded aghast. He continued, “Yeah the rich kids weren’t laughing because they could afford a sense of humor. They had a sense of humor because they didn’t spend so much time worrying about the things they don’t have and enjoyed life. I mean - maybe that was a result of having more money, but you don’t need money to get it. If you focused more on what you do have, and learn to appreciate those things then you can spend more time finding the humor inside yourself”. It was something that I had never even considered until that moment. I felt so foolish spending all of this time hoping to buy something that was within me this whole time. I just needed to get it out. I thanked my friend and knew what I had to do next. I took all of the money that I had saved up and spent the coming years of my life seeking out any doctor to who help me find the humor inside me. Many turned me down and thought that I had misunderstood something I had read on the internet, but I was sure eventually would listen to my pleas and help. After many years of X-rays, MRIs, and exploratory surgeries from back alley medical students nobody was able to find any humor in me. I’m not really sure what the point of this story was. I’ve spent all my money on those procedures and I really need a job. You people clearly need someone to produce and manage quality content for your site. Let’s work something out?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You can find some of my personal projects here:
Youtube.com/MrPowerScripts&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;My resume with more detailed information is attached. Let’s do great things together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I showed this to her before I sent it. She thought I was insane. That is still up for debate. I received an email within a couple of days to come interview with their director of marketing. She never received a reply. The dude seemed to like me. We talked about companies we thought had killer marketing. We discussed my personal projects like the MrPowerScripts youtube channel. We hit it off pretty well and he asked me to come back for an interview with the CEO. Fast forward a few days and I’m in the room with the head honcho. He drilled into me a bit harder than the marketing guy, but I was feeling it that day. I remember at one point he said: “you talk a really good game”. You’re damn right I do skip. At least on that day, I did. That’s exactly the moment that I knew I had the job. There was just one problem. I didn’t actually want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been working from home for several years at this point. I was also looking for a new job at the time, but I had no interest to come into an office every single day. That’s the kind of person they were looking for. When they called me back a couple days later to offer me the position I tried to explain that I’d be happy to do all of the work at home. There was absolutely no reason for me to commute every day to create content. Marketing dude was not flexible on that, and ultimately we went our separate ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the story doesn’t completely end on a sour note. My then girlfriend eventually did take the next step in her career and found a much better job than her current one. She also managed to make a strong follow up after that by finding a better boyfriend that doesn’t do stuff like snake her on job offers that she wanted. Lessons learned all around.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/funny-resume-story/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/funny-resume-story/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Create a Reddit bot that gets you all the karma. It's easy as py(thon)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;You may only be interested in the source code. Which you can find here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/reddit-karma-farming-bot&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/reddit-karma-farming-bot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2020-reddit-karma-bot-update-video&quot;&gt;2020 Reddit Karma Bot Update Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reddit Karma Bot has been updated for 2020 with many new features. Like shadowban detection, charts, and other cool features. Check out the new video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;nWYRGXesb3I&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-reddit-karma-bot&quot;&gt;The Reddit Karma Bot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a video a while ago about a small bot I made for Reddit. The goal of making the bot was to figure out a way to farm karma on Reddit. Earning the sites social currency (karma) without having to actually do any real work. Think of it as a digital reality show star. I managed to put together a very simple bot that had surprisingly successful results. &lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;8DrOERA5FGc&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take much code thanks to some python libraries that did most of the work. The bot would repost old threads from a year ago to earn post karma and used a Markov chain based learning algorithm to generate somewhat relevant replies to comments. It wasn’t perfect, but it worked well enough for longer than I thought it would. You can see in the first video how one of the bot iterations was able to farm up a significant karma count in just a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2019 UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt; Check out the 2.0 version of this bot in the video below!
&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;CCMGHepPBso&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karma on Reddit matters. It allows you to open new features on the site, and is considered by many as a sign of credibility/contribution to the communities (or subreddits). Which makes having older accounts with high karma counts and activity very attractive to people who want to do fun, nefarious, or profitable activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made a technical video that covered the code which made it all happen. It’s shows how easy it is to create a reddit bot. See if your bot can learn well enough to farm karma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;KgWsqKkDEtI&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out to be a much simpler project than I thought it would be. The bot had a lot of people replying its comments as if it was a real person. Which I found quite amusing. The bot was eventually found out because everything about its footprint seemed VERY mechanical. Comments were sent out every 10 minutes exactly. Posts were reposted from exactly one year ago. It was obvious when looking at the user profile there was something driving this account like clockwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t set out to create the perfect bot, and the code definietly reflects that. There’s a lot of room for improvment that could have allowed the bot to live a longer life. For instance, I could have randomized the date when I stole old posts to repost them rather than doing it exactly one year ago. Also, randomizing the comments and simulating some period of activity. Maybe decreasing postings significantly during a period of time to simulate the bot is “at work”. Unless I wanted to simulate the bot having an office job. In which case I would increase the activity during that period. The bots comments seemed to become wildly ridiculous strings of random text when they returned back too large. Shorter responses from the bot often times seemed to be more relevant to the comment it was attempting to reply to. I could have had it cycle through creating responses and discard anything longer than a fixed character count. This is one of the key clues that led to the end of the bot. People saw it posting large paragraphs of nonsense and began checking the post history to make sure this account wasn’t having a stroke. Some noticed the pattern of postings and then made it their job to report every single comment from the bot, and make comments indicating that the posts were coming from a bot. Eventually, the account was banned entirely. With some adjustments I think there’s a chance the bot could have lived a long life on Reddit before anyone was keen to the fact it was really a cold dead machine looking for validation on the internet. Like reality show stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, all I really accomplished is a small proof of concept. When you’re interacting on social media you might be part of social experiment without even realizing it. That would be the least of anyones concerns though. I don’t think it would be too difficult to create bots that apear as everyday people but have some minor tweaks to serve different purposes. Such as suggesting certain products to buy when a relevant topic is brought up. Influening poltical discussions with misinformation. I’m sure there’s plenty of other purposes with money, influence, or other motives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battle between robots and humans is already raging on even if it doesn’t involve Arnold Schwarzenegger coming to the rescue. Actually, he posts quite a bit on Reddit so maybe we’re living out a reality closer to Terminator than we actually thought. The world wide web is still very much the wild wild west when it comes to information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/create-a-reddit-bot-to-farm-karma/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/create-a-reddit-bot-to-farm-karma/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Blog blog blog blog</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Finally! I have a blog set up on my site thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now&quot;&gt;Jekyll-now&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out!`&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://mrpowerscripts.com/Hello-World/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mrpowerscripts.com/Hello-World/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>