<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-08T21:09:05+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MrPowerScripts</title><subtitle>Learn. Code. Grow.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Battle Nation Live</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/battle-nation-live/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Battle Nation Live" /><published>2020-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T17:38:39+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/battle-nation-live</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/battle-nation-live/">&lt;p&gt;Battle Nation Live is a discord variety show bot that I wrote a few years ago. It was the first real discord bot that I built. I was using Discord.js, and the code is atrocious. But it still works! And I’ve set it up to run on the MrPowerScripts discord server so that people can try it out any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;battle-nation-live-overview&quot;&gt;Battle Nation Live Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get the quickest overview of how it works by checking out &lt;a href=&quot;https://bnl.mrpowerscripts.com/&quot;&gt;https://bnl.mrpowerscripts.com/&lt;/a&gt;, the original website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-battle-nation-live-work&quot;&gt;How does Battle Nation Live work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does the bot work? Join “The Show” voice channel and then run the&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;!signup&lt;/code&gt; command, which adds you to the queue for the show. Once it is your turn, you will automatically get the “Live” discord role, which allows you to use the mic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone else remains muted, and it’s your turn to shine! Except there’s one catch. Everyone else gets to vote on whether you get to keep the mic or not using emoji during the performance. If you lose the vote at the end of the round, it goes to the next person! Rounds last 15 seconds, so you need to keep everyone entertained if you want to keep the mic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this whole process of users signing up,  changing the role of who can use the mic, rotating people through the queue., and doing the emoji vote counts are managed by the bot. It’s pretty neat. I like to think of it as American Idol for discord, or some other singing or variety contest. Americas Got Talent for discord? I don’t know I never really watched those shows. But it’s possible to have these kinds of contests on discord as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;battle-nation-live-source-code&quot;&gt;Battle Nation Live source code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is super terrible. I was learning a lot of stuff about node and js at the time, as I still am. But I’m going to share it anyway. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/battle-nation-live-discord-bot&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/battle-nation-live-discord-bot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you want to test your skills, joins the MrPowerScripts Discord server (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/mrps-discord&quot;&gt;https://bit.ly/mrps-discord&lt;/a&gt;) where the bot is running 24/7. You can always hop on the mic at the Battle Nation Live show. lol I should never be allowed to name things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">Battle Nation Live is a discord variety show bot that I wrote a few years ago. It was the first real discord bot that I built. I was using Discord.js, and the code is atrocious. But it still works! And I’ve set it up to run on the MrPowerScripts discord server so that people can try it out any time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why the name MrPowerScripts?</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/why-mrpowerscripts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why the name MrPowerScripts?" /><published>2020-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T01:20:02+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/why-mrpowerscripts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/why-mrpowerscripts/">&lt;p&gt;So why did I choose to name all of this…. stuff, MrPowerScripts? The youtube channel, the blog, the podcast. Everything is MrPowerscripts. The reality is that I fucked up, and I haven’t been a massive fan of it for a long time. I lacked the foresight to see that it would grow into more… stuff. I had to pick something unless I wanted some long-ass garbled string as my youtube URL. Subscribe to my channel youtube.com/sdfJIOfdsafhHJdshafo yeah, okay. But the fact it was a video platform had a considerable influence on why I chose this name instead of something cool like Tech Warriors, or Scriptiverse. Hmmm, I guess It could have been a lot worse. I shouldn’t be allowed to name anything. But it was inspired by someone else who made educational videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-internet-is-amazing&quot;&gt;The. internet is amazing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, there was this time before the internet. It was fucking terrible. I lived years of my life without access to all the world’s knowledge. If you wanted to know some weird facts about a random building in Italy, you had to read it in a book, know someone from Italy, or go to Italy. Which is all fine and dandy unless you’re a fucking five-year-old. Or however old I was. Do you know what it’s like looking through an encyclopedia as a child? They’re thick and wordy. Are you a visual learner? Get fucked kiddo. There were no random youtube videos by vacationers with six views about some obscure building in the middle fuck all nowhere, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;encyclopedia-bricktanica&quot;&gt;Encyclopedia bricktanica&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s if you were lucky enough to have an encyclopedia set full of random info. Look up how much those big encyclopedia sets used to cost. Hell, they’re still like $800 on Amazon. They would sell them on TV at odd hours, and you would have to pay with installments of $19.99 a month for the rest of your damn life.  I’m not even exaggerating &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/technology/2012/03/the-encyclopedia-britannica-was-expensive-useless-and-exploitative-im-glad-its-gone.html&quot;&gt;people on major publications have written happily about the demise of one of the major brands of the day Encyclopedia Britanica&lt;/a&gt;. TL;DR Massive paperweights, and not as cool as Mr. cool dude in their advertisements leads us to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;SbQFXWlVpIU&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, okay, the world’s knowledge wasn’t just within those overpriced organic bricks, but wow, I hated those things. I needed a moment for some retro-hate. I was so excited to find an article bashing them! There is something far far better that served as a crucial role in information exchange. Libraries!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-loved-the-library&quot;&gt;I loved the library&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library was AMAZING, and an endless supply of information was available. They were always changing as new books came and went. I have the best memories of hanging out at libraries. I would spend hours poking through books looking for the ones I wanted to read late into the night. I sometimes left with my backpack full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was lucky, I could find excellent illustrations in books about really complicated stuff that I wanted to learn. And being more of a visual learner, understanding advanced or sophisticated ideas through reading was a challenge. Reading comprehension is a fundamental skill, and thankfully I had access to an infinite number of books to keep me curious and challenged at a young age. But my brain is probably a bit broken because I found television programs with graphics and animations accelerated my understanding of the subject matter much faster. Books I love you, but sometimes video is better. A picture can be worth a thousand words and good luck fitting a thousand words into a concise paragraph with neat transitions and sound effects. Maybe I just like powerpoints?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rise-of-the-science-giants&quot;&gt;The Rise of the Science Giants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educational science programs made the “hard” stuff seem more straightforward and did so in an entertaining way. Television shows I grew up with like “Bill Nye the Science Guy” and” Beakmans World” exploded in popularity during the ’90s. They were so popular we had days in school where we watched episodes to give students an overview of subjects before covering them more in-depth using the book materials. Video-based education was a booming segment in visual media throughout the decade, growing along with the internet. And these faces happened to pop up in the right place at the right now. But there was someone making science education videos waaaaay before Bill and Beakman brought their quirky personalities to the TV screens. Someone who was pretty much the complete opposite of them. Mr. Wizard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mr-wizard-doesnt-have-time-for-your-shit-kid&quot;&gt;Mr. Wizard doesn’t have time for your shit, kid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Wizard had two science educations shows. One from 1951-1965 (71-72) in black &amp;amp; white called “Watch Mr. Wizard.” And he later returned to TV with a second show called “Mr. Wizards World” that ran from 1983-1990. Very original name, Mr. Beakman. Mr. Wizard was there teaching simple science concepts on TV with real examples that you could watch while having someone talk through the explanation with you. Like you had a personal teacher that you could pause and rewind. I remember watching the show in passing at a very young age. I didn’t know how scheduled worked at the time. I don’t even think there was a TV channel for schedules at the time. You had to buy a TV guide at the grocery store. I realize now kids are going to have no fucking clue what any of that means, and I’m starting to realize just how barbaric the ’90s were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;play-with-fire-and-youre-gonna-get-learned&quot;&gt;Play with fire, and you’re gonna get learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, It would happen to be on TV sometimes, and I was lucky to catch it playing. And the thing I loved most about it is that I clearly remember understanding that this stuff was REAL. You could mix things and make them explode! He was always lighting things on fire, and I generally found that to be incredibly cool at the time. I was not the brightest lightbulb. He regularly taught us that the materials in the world we live in interact with each other in neat ways, and we have tools and techniques to detect and measure it all. Well, not all of it. Still a whole lot of “hmm, that’s fucky” when it comes to the sciences. But through the persistence of experimentation and iteration, we discover new things that make us go “hmm, that’s fucky”. And then sometimes, penicillin, because “whoops.” The world is magical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mr-wizard-helped-make-mrpowerscripts&quot;&gt;Mr Wizard helped make MrPowerScripts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as I was trying to figure out a name for this new youtube channel that I needed to name, I thought of the first video educator that I encountered. Someone I’ll never meet, but who had a significant impact in sparking my curiosity about the world and sharing it in a fun, simple, and engaging way in a time where access to information was limited compared to today. The channel was only going to be about Powershell scripts at the time, and so MrPowerScripts became the channel name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always remembered him as a bit of a hard-nosed teacher, and it was funny to find the video below of Mr. Wizard being a jerk while trying to help kids learn. That… explains a lot now that I think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;QWGjjw0ZwXk&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">So why did I choose to name all of this…. stuff, MrPowerScripts? The youtube channel, the blog, the podcast. Everything is MrPowerscripts. The reality is that I fucked up, and I haven’t been a massive fan of it for a long time. I lacked the foresight to see that it would grow into more… stuff. I had to pick something unless I wanted some long-ass garbled string as my youtube URL. Subscribe to my channel youtube.com/sdfJIOfdsafhHJdshafo yeah, okay. But the fact it was a video platform had a considerable influence on why I chose this name instead of something cool like Tech Warriors, or Scriptiverse. Hmmm, I guess It could have been a lot worse. I shouldn’t be allowed to name anything. But it was inspired by someone else who made educational videos.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Working from home is overrated and you need to know why</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/home-office-overrated/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working from home is overrated and you need to know why" /><published>2020-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-01T15:28:53+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/home-office-overrated</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/home-office-overrated/">&lt;p&gt;It’s trendy because of the global pandemic, but people have likely learned by now that working from home isn’t so great. Having worked from home for seven-ish years now, I feel very comfortable saying that. And it’s not only because I’m not wearing pants as I write this. It’s also because I’m laying in bed, with my heated lumbar support. I’m very comfortable saying all of this. So let me tell you why working from home isn’t so great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I always have trouble deciding when I want to get up. “Be there at 8 am sharp,” was my mental mantra for almost a decade. Then I started working from home, and I have a window from 8 am to 11 am when I need to get started. I didn’t have to think about it too much before.  It was so simple. Sometimes I’m up all night trying to decide when I want to get up. What am I supposed to do with so much freedom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The freedom it offers can be exhausting. Sometimes I’ll wake up early, by accident, and I don’t want to start working yet. But I need to do SOMETHING. So I’ll go to the kitchen to make some delicious eggs and bacon, but find no eggs! And this happens all too often because I have the time to prepare well made delightful food every morning, and the eggs go so fast! I’ll have to endure a morning walk to the local store with cars lined up for blocks honking erratically. How inconvenient is that? I always prefer to have my walks after a nice lunch when everything in the streets is calm and the afternoon sun is shining. They don’t warn you about these complications that a work from home job can create. I mean, it has destroyed some of my favorite activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to do laundry ALL THE TIME. I had my closet bursting with casual business attire. You know, the kind of attire that lets other people know you’re a decent human being. With slight style variations, to also let people know you’re not a mindless cog working within a culturally suffocating environment that values conformity for streamlined behavior that maximizes profit. But now I don’t have any of that!!! Who will see my pencil tie to know I like writing? I no longer have a second set of clothing geared towards my office persona, and it dramatically reduced the time I spend washing clothes, hanging them to dry, and folding them. Alright, alright, I’ll admit this was a bit of a joke cause don’t fold my clothes. But now my opportunities to not do it are far fewer! It’s devastating and only adds to the time I spend worrying about what to do with all the time I have!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those stresses got to me when I started working remotely. I was beginning to lose it, and now I take breaks regularly. Almost every hour I’ll go on a mini walk, or take the time to stretch, make a delicious snack, or something else to keep me occupied through these daily dramas I’m encountering now. But it gets even worse than that!! These inconveniences follow me everywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to escape these troubles by going to local cafes with good wifi, prepared dishes, and no digital loitering policy. No longer would I have to worry about food running out, distractions from home, or anything else perturbing my well-being through work. Or, so I thought! Do you know how hard it can be on you when your favorite barista isn’t working, and the new person filling in doesn’t know how to add cocoa flakes around the milky heart shape on the top of your coffee? And you have to sit there trying to get work done taking sips, but you don’t get that extra chocolately bit of flavor and texture in each sip? It’s devastating. I’ve had to scour my hours to find super baristas. And I call in each morning now to make sure AT LEAST one of them is working before I waste ten minutes walking over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody is telling the truth about this stuff.  You hear about how fantastic working from home is, but until you’ve spent time living the lifestyle, it’s easy to overlook the less obvious pitfalls. But thankfully, I’m here to tell you the truth about working from home, so you don’t have to trouble yourself looking for one of these jobs and flooding the market with competition.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">It’s trendy because of the global pandemic, but people have likely learned by now that working from home isn’t so great. Having worked from home for seven-ish years now, I feel very comfortable saying that. And it’s not only because I’m not wearing pants as I write this. It’s also because I’m laying in bed, with my heated lumbar support. I’m very comfortable saying all of this. So let me tell you why working from home isn’t so great!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My code is in the GitHub Arctic Code Vault</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/github-arctic-code-vault/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My code is in the GitHub Arctic Code Vault" /><published>2020-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T13:19:45+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/github-arctic-code-vault</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/github-arctic-code-vault/">&lt;p&gt;I opened up GitHub the other day to find I had a new badge called Artic Code Vault Contributor. Excuse me? Wat? Some of you might be thinking, “of course! The Artic Code Vault”. But I had no  fucking  clue what that meant in the slightest. So I did what most people do when they’re trying to shake the dumb from their brain. I Googled, “What is the Artic Code Vault?”. And this is what I saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;fzI9FNjXQ0o&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow. My code is literally chilling inside an island called Svalbard, housed deep in an old mine to be preserved for the future of humanity. If that doesn’t sound like some wild James Bond shit, I don’t know what does, but it doesn’t matter MY CODE IS IN  A FREAKING ARTIC CODE VAULT IN THE ARTIC IN A VAULT THAT”S SUPER COLD HOW COOL IS THAT?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below freezing. I couldn’t find any specific information about the Arctic Code Vault’s temperature, but it’s probably safe to say it’s below freezing. And that’s pretty fucking cool. So what code is stored in the Artic Code Vault? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/reddit-karma-farming-bot&quot;&gt;The Reddit Karma Farming Bot&lt;/a&gt;, The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/meme-cd&quot;&gt;Continuous Meme Delivery Project&lt;/a&gt;, and my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/storage&quot;&gt;generic script storage&lt;/a&gt; repo. None of that was worth preserving for future generations of humans. Unless future generations will need to spam Reddit with puppy pictures for fake internet points. Okay, maybe at least that one was worth saving. KARMA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What an amazing feat of human achievement, and I’m super happy to be part of this plan put forth because we’re probably going to fuck this planet up so bad it’s gonna cause a fun evolutionary reset. Hopefully, chicken people get a shot at dominating the world next. Working on open-source software with some odd wing-friendly keyboards, and the Artic Code Vault will definitely give them a head start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can all agree that this is a monumental feat of human achievement of preserving technological advancements and culture. Just like the Svalbard Global Seed Vault which is not far from the GitHub Arctic Code Vault. All of these endeavors are 5 stars, right? Uhhhh then why does the Svalbard Global Seed Vault have a 4.6 rating on Google Maps? HOW IS THIS NOT 6 STARS??? You can look at it right on the map embedded below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;map-responsive&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d1483769.3529564082!2d11.008897656105544!3d78.2356771916149!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x459c54abde19eff1%3A0x15fa4670a5924662!2sSvalbard%20Global%20Seed%20Vault!5e1!3m2!1sen!2spt!4v1595012008749!5m2!1sen!2spt&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;false&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHO COULD POSSIBLY THINK THIS IS NOT AMAZING?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/code-vault-review-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/code-vault-review-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/code-vault-review-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/code-vault-review-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/code-vault-review-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/code-vault-review-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/code-vault-review-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what? Fuck it. Do the elites have a Patreon I can support to speed this all up?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">I opened up GitHub the other day to find I had a new badge called Artic Code Vault Contributor. Excuse me? Wat? Some of you might be thinking, “of course! The Artic Code Vault”. But I had no fucking clue what that meant in the slightest. So I did what most people do when they’re trying to shake the dumb from their brain. I Googled, “What is the Artic Code Vault?”. And this is what I saw.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Automated Reality Channel Ep2 Planning</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-two/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automated Reality Channel Ep2 Planning" /><published>2020-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-20T08:19:56+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-two/">&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-one/&quot;&gt;a single episode of the automated reality channel&lt;/a&gt; processed and published live. It put waaaaay too much effort into something that probably isn’t going to go anywhere. It worked through! I did get episode 1 out the door, but it didn’t reach the project’s real goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to collaborate with content creators to create the content assets that the episodes used. Instead, I had it sing mary had a little lamb, and I showed off my atrocious paint.net skills. For episode two, I would like to accomplish the actual goal. It’s collaborating time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most significant part of the “actual goal” was that paying content creators would happen through the Patreon donations. I even &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MrPowerScripts/mrps-discord-powerbot&quot;&gt;set up a bot&lt;/a&gt; so that people who were Patreon supporters could vote on ideas for the videos. Allowing people who were funding the content creation to have a say in how that content was created. But there’s not enough community or project interest to make that work. And I had no Patreon supports to help fund the content creations or vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I got my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/MrPowerScripts&quot;&gt;Patreon supporter&lt;/a&gt;!!! Shout out to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Asgaroth 😼&lt;/code&gt; on Discord. So, we have a budget now. Of $5 lol. It’s not much, but maybe it can help us reach the goal! Even if it’s as simple as &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/arc-episode-one/&quot;&gt;episode one was&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, I’m going to try &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration&quot;&gt;starting small and iterating&lt;/a&gt;. I would like to find an artist to create two images of - well, they can be anything. As long as those things can talk. And find someone to write a short narrative between the two characters. Are you a writer or an artist who thinks it would be cool to be part of episode 2 even though we obviously have a tiny budget? Join us on discord and have a chat with us! https://bit.ly/mrps-discord&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">I was pretty happy to get a single episode of the automated reality channel processed and published live. It put waaaaay too much effort into something that probably isn’t going to go anywhere. It worked through! I did get episode 1 out the door, but it didn’t reach the project’s real goal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MrPowerScripts.com is a Progressive Web App (PWA)</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/my-pwa-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MrPowerScripts.com is a Progressive Web App (PWA)" /><published>2020-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-13T18:18:47+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/my-pwa-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/my-pwa-website/">&lt;p&gt;I finally did it. MrPowerScripts.com is now a Progressive Web App. Did it take long? Nope. A couple of hours. I was trying to do it from memory. It should have taken about 20 minutes. Whoops. So it’s there, it’s working, it’s incredible, and what the hell is a PWA?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-progressive-web-app-pwa&quot;&gt;What is a progressive web app? (PWA)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ever surf a website, and you like the content? And you would love to get notifications about when new content is released? Or the ability to interact with the site offline?  So you check to see if they have an app, and if you’re lucky, they do! Cause that’s all the stuff that apps do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why do you need to download an entirely new app? The content was right there already. Native apps do provide additional advantages. They have access to local resources, processes can run in the background. You can’t do all that with a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the content was RIGHT THERE ALREADY. Why do I have to open up a different app to download a new app to get a better experience with the content I was literally just looking at?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you could get the benefits of a native app directly from the website itself? So users click a button on your website that turns the site into a native app type of experience. That’s what a Progressive Web App does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWA support comes directly from browsers, so they work on both mobile and desktop. Progressive web apps turn your website into a native app-like experience on mobile, and they can also be installed as a “desktop app.” on your computer. Not every browser supports this feature. For instance, Chrome fully supports Progressive Web Apps on mobile and desktop versions. Firefox mobile has some support for PWAs, but they’ve had a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1407202&quot;&gt;three-year-old open issue&lt;/a&gt; for adding support in their desktop version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see which browsers support the required &lt;a href=&quot;https://caniuse.com/#search=PWA&quot;&gt;features for PWAs here&lt;/a&gt;. The interesting part is that the Microsoft Edge browser has full support for PWAs. In contrast, Apple’s Safari browser has no support. Why is that interesting? If you read about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_web_application&quot;&gt;history of PWAs&lt;/a&gt; they were conceptualized as the first “app” experience on the iPhone. Though they faded out of favor for the “native” solution, we’re now using. iPhone apps were supposed to be web apps build with basic HTML, CSS, and javascript through AJAX calls. Despite dragging along through the years, there’s a wide range of growing use and support for PWAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-advantages-of-a-pwa-vs-native-app&quot;&gt;What are the advantages of a PWA vs. Native app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native apps will always perform better, but many types of websites can benefit from adding PWA support. Such as content-focused sites, like news outlets. Adding PWA support will let users add your “web app” to their mobile home screen or desktop shortcuts for quick access. It also allows your website to open up as a full screen. So to the user, it will have an app-like experience. They can access it with the click of a button, and they’ll have the full phone real estate to view the content like a native app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, through the use of a service worker, you can enable various caching strategies, so that content can be cached for offline viewing. Or the content can even be updated in the background. Allowing for the new content to open quickly. New standards like Trusted Web Activity (TWA) and tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa/&quot;&gt;Bubblewrap by Google Chrome Labs team&lt;/a&gt; enable you to quickly turn your PWA website into an APK. Then you can upload your PWA APK to the Google Play store, where people can download it like a real native app. Also, like native apps, you’ll be able to send mobile and desktop notifications. Again, like a real native app!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, we’ll see more support for Progressive Web Apps, as they help bridge the gap between native and web experiences. With the use of good old fashioned Javascript, HTML, and CSS. Native apps will always have their place because of the performance and resource limitations of PWAs. But you still have access to a lot of great features like notifications, and offline viewing. Also, PWAs can be installed from desktop browsers with a simple click. Can you install a play store app on your desktop that easily? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pwas-are-here-to-stay&quot;&gt;PWAs are here to stay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWAs aren’t going to go away any time soon, and the support is only growing. Many major websites like Twitter, Facebook, and popular open-source projects like Discourse already support PWAs. Exciting tools like Bubblewrap will help increase the versatility of PWAs. And we’ll likely continue to see standards like TWA develop to blur the lines between the native app and PWA experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need help turning your website into a PWA? Join me &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/mrps-discord.&quot;&gt;on Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">I finally did it. MrPowerScripts.com is now a Progressive Web App. Did it take long? Nope. A couple of hours. I was trying to do it from memory. It should have taken about 20 minutes. Whoops. So it’s there, it’s working, it’s incredible, and what the hell is a PWA?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Simple tips for great tutorial videos</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/tutorial-video-tips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simple tips for great tutorial videos" /><published>2020-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-10T10:16:31+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/tutorial-video-tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/tutorial-video-tips/">&lt;p&gt;So I’ve had my youtube channel for over eight years now. Am I a “YouTuber”? Not really. The channel is pretty small, and I don’t post content as often as I used to. Have I improved in those eight years? You’re damn right, and that’s what I really love most about the channel. My hard work is on display. I figured it was a good time to critique my first video and share some of the things I learned about creating tutorial videos on youtube.
&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;2pGEpfnCshg&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I created my first video, I didn’t really know anything about video editing, recording audio, performing format conversions, how youtube worked. Basically, I didn’t know anything. I scrambled enough information together through the internet to put together a simple tutorial that shared a Powershell cheat sheet that I used. Not very groundbreaking, but I had to start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learned-making-tutorial-videos&quot;&gt;What I learned making tutorial videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick list of tips that will help you create great tutorial videos. Obviously, I have my own sort of approach with making tutorial videos. I like to focus on showing code, or simple images that may help illustrate a point. Everyone has their own style, and everyone has style preferences. So, if your style is different than mine these suggestions may not be helpful, but maybe they’ll help you consider some ideas you haven’t thought of already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Good audio is critical and poor sound is distracting. You want your voice to be clear and consistent throughout the video and without random background noises that detracts from the experience. It’s worth investing in all the new mid-range condenser mics available these days. It will make a huge difference. Also, learning how to apply filters like condensers and noise limiters can drastically improve the performance of even lower range audio devices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your voice is audio. How you talk matters. Speak clearly, and project your voice. It may seem weird projecting your voice in an empty room, but that extra kick can improve the video experience. If you sound excited and interested in the content, it will appear more exciting and interesting. This can take a lot of practice, but the results are worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make it mobile-friendly. Mobile media consumption far surpasses desktop consumption. If what your showing can’t be viewed through mobile, then you’re leaving a lot of potential viewers out. Increase font sizes, zoom in with browsers. Whatever you need to do to make the content your showing clear on mobile should be done.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do favors with your editing. You can save people a lot of time with your editing. I’ve been able to cut a full five minutes out of videos that were just filled with pauses and “umms” that distracted from the experience and wasted time. People are watching your tutorial so they can do something, and the faster you can give them the information they need, the faster they can get back to doing that thing. Nobody has ever complained about weird cuts or the mouse jumpting around because I removed a couple seconds of the video in editing. .But I’ve received a lot of praise for how clean and concise my videos are since I began improving my editing process. A bit of extra time editing can save tons of time for viewers through the life of the video.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep adding to this list as I remember more details I’ve found helpful over the years. It’s essential to go back and critique our own works if we want to continue improving. Am I the best video creator on the planet? Not even close. But the time spent on this hobby has helped me in many ways. Every new video I created was an opportunity to analyze my own efforts and established a new baseline for me to improve upon. And the proof is there. It took me eight years to go from bad to OK, and I’m sure I’ll learn about more I can improve upon in the next eight years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">So I’ve had my youtube channel for over eight years now. Am I a “YouTuber”? Not really. The channel is pretty small, and I don’t post content as often as I used to. Have I improved in those eight years? You’re damn right, and that’s what I really love most about the channel. My hard work is on display. I figured it was a good time to critique my first video and share some of the things I learned about creating tutorial videos on youtube.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Feng Shui Bracelet - The greatest youtube commercial ever</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/feng-shui-bracelet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feng Shui Bracelet - The greatest youtube commercial ever" /><published>2020-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-14T00:25:05+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/feng-shui-bracelet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/feng-shui-bracelet/">&lt;p&gt;Do you want to learn more about Feng Shui and how to use it to shake $20 from people’s pockets? Well, I have the deal of a lifetime for you. Reading this blog post is going to unlock real wealth and happiness in your life. Not that fake knock of wealth and happiness. So let’s learn more about Feng Shui and how you can attain everything you’ve ever wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-youtube-commercial-is-going-to-change-your-life&quot;&gt;This youtube commercial is going to change your life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across this life-changing commercial while trying to watch something else. I forget what it was, but it wasn’t going to change my life like this commercial did. The ad starts off with a man asking me if I’ve heard about Feng Shui and how it can affect my energy flow. I have, but the exhilarating background music makes me feel like I’m about to learn more than I could imagine. Noel here seems pretty confident he’s about to change my life. Let’s do this, Noel. Lay some Feng Shui game down on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- (1) video wrapper --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-video&quot; data-embed=&quot;to5llr46LhA&quot;&gt; 
 
    &lt;!-- (2) the &quot;play&quot; button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;play-button&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
     
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;keep-your-eye-on-the-bar&quot;&gt;Keep your eye on the bar&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully this Feng Shui commercial included a flashing bar above narration text displayed on the screen. My eyes kept wandering, but the bar helped keep me focused on the explanatory captions. It also included helpful choices for words and phrases highlighted in yellow that really emphasized the positive aspects of Feng Shui. But don’t let it totally distract you from the beautiful, relevant b-rolls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;free-feng-shui-home-office-tips&quot;&gt;Free Feng Shui home office tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video, released Nov 3, 2019, lets us know that Feng Shui originated in China. Then two months later, the coronavirus, which also came from China, spread to the world. Having people trapped at home would make them more likely to see these Feng Shui adverts and be susceptible to messages of increasing wealth and prosperity. Am I saying this company deliberately spread coronavirus so people will care more about Feng Shui? Yes, it’s entirely possible given how 2020 has played out so far. It would be the least surprising thing at this point. But can you really be mad at them? They’re about to give away Feng Shui tips FOR FREE. We’re getting a great deal here, people. So here are your 5 free Feng Shui home office tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always sit so there is a solid wall behind your back. This ensures that you have support in your life. Never sit with your back towards the window.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always place fax machines, telephone, computers, and cash registers in the southeast wealth sector to attract more prospective businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Arrange your desk so you always have a clear view of the door, preferably facing the door. If it is impossible to arrange, then hang a small mirror so you can clearly see the reflection of the door.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Never put a shelf over your desk. The shelf symbolizes the burdens of the world coming down upon you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try to keep sharp items such as paper cutters, scissors, or any sharp corners of a machine away from the desk. Make sure they are not pointing at the desk. Keep all the sharp objects hidden away from view in a drawer or closet. The sharp edges symbolize the cutting of a knife, which is a disapproving finger pointing at you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AMAZING. Five free Feng Shui tips for your home office. You’re probably thinking all that sounds like a load of horse shit, but that’s exactly what someone with an empty southeast wealth sector would think. Loser. I even sawed off all the corners of my desk to be extra safe. But what can we do outside of our home office? I need to take this magical energy with me EVERYWHERE I go. Is it possible? Can it be? You’re damn right it’s possible, and the advertisement doesn’t waste time to jump right into the alternatives, like the Feng Shui Black Obsidian Bracelet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feng-shui-black-obsidian-bracelet&quot;&gt;Feng Shui Black Obsidian Bracelet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy shit, you can literally carry Feng Shui around on your wrist with the Feng Shui Black Obsidian Bracelet. The bracelet is made of two POWERFUL talismans. First, the Pixiu talisman, which is also known as Pi Yao. The other element is black Obsidian. Wait, that’s not two talismans. You just called it an element, where is the other talisman? WHO CARES let’s go over some benefits of Pixiu and black Obsidian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attract-fortune-and-wealth-with-pixiu-talisman&quot;&gt;Attract fortune and wealth with Pixiu talisman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video tells us Pixiu is known to bring fortune and attract wealth. I mean those are kinda the same thing, right? I’m not sure why you said the same thing in two different ways, but I like the sound of both of them. This is a combo deal talisman. Incredible two for one talisman value. Then there’s the black Obsidian, which is known to give protection and shield against negativity. Which is so important in this day and age where haters are everywhere. Like haters in the video youtube comments who bought the bracelet and found it didn’t do anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img style=&quot;object-fit: contain&quot; src=&quot;/images/feng-shui-comments.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;block-out-your-haters&quot;&gt;Block out your haters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This negative energy needs to be blocked out, and thankfully the bracelet has that critical Obsidian element. The video also goes on to state that Black Obsidian is known to increase self-control and makes one embrace their true self. Which might be why those people bought this bracelet in the first place, they simply didn’t have the self-control they needed. And now, with this bracelet, they definitely won’t make any further impulsive decisions. Truly amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most amazing part of all this is that Noel discovered the bracelet when he met Master Xi. See, Noel was a garbage collector before Master Xi put him onto the Feng Shui Black Obsidian bracelet. Noel found a wallet on the ground with more money than he could earn. Did that wallet have more money than he could make in a day? A week? A year? WE DON’T KNOW AND WHO CARES. Stop asking so many questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;master-xi-is-a-really-dope-name-to-be-honest&quot;&gt;Master Xi is a really dope name, to be honest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s important here is that Noel was honest and gave the wallet back to the owner, who happened to be Master Xi. That’s when Master Xi rewarded Noel by giving him the Feng Shui Black Obsidian bracelet. Immediately from here on out, Noel’s life totally changed. And even many other people told Noel that the bracelet changed their life too. It also healed their illness. What illness? Again, WHO CARES, this thing is covered in gold and Obsidian. Keep your eye on the blinking bar and read the text. This isn’t a Q&amp;amp;A session. Noel is here to teach you how to cure whatever the fuck you got. It even provided more work opportunities for some and generally made people feel more confident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if you’ve realized yet, but this bracelet is fucking amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;einstein-would-totally-wear-the-feng-shui-bracelet&quot;&gt;Einstein would totally wear the Feng Shui bracelet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still skeptical? Noel goes on to implore you to recognize the importance of the energy in and around us. He quotes Einstein’s famous equation E = mc&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; to remind us that matter is tightly related to energy. Energy shapes matter, so if we can shape our energy, we can begin to shape our future. That’s right, the bracelet is backed up by SCIENCE. Einstein said it himself. You gonna sit there with your broke ass calling Einstein stupid? Why shape your energy with a healthy diet and exercise when all you really need is to carry around some Feng Shui on your wrist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noel isn’t a lowly garbage collector anymore. Now he works closely with Master Xi to bring these bracelets to the world. Which may sound like he got roped into a multi-level marketing scheme if you’re the type of hater that keeps pointy things on their desk. Thankfully the Obsidian blocks out all that hater energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-feel-richer-simply-by-looking-at-the-bracelet&quot;&gt;I feel richer simply by looking at the bracelet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we reach the end of the video, and all you have to do is click the link and wait for your Feng Shui black Obsidian bracelet. What a fantastic journey of transformation we were able to make in three minutes and thirty-eight seconds. For only $20 you, and everyone else, can have access to all the wealth, health, and prosperity you dreamed of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">Do you want to learn more about Feng Shui and how to use it to shake $20 from people’s pockets? Well, I have the deal of a lifetime for you. Reading this blog post is going to unlock real wealth and happiness in your life. Not that fake knock of wealth and happiness. So let’s learn more about Feng Shui and how you can attain everything you’ve ever wanted.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oh My Gosh turn your PWA into an Android app in the Google play store</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh My Gosh turn your PWA into an Android app in the Google play store" /><published>2020-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/pwa-to-apk-with-twa/">&lt;p&gt;Do you have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_web_application&quot;&gt;Progressive Web App (PWA)&lt;/a&gt; that you would love to see in Google’s Android play store? You can make that happen today! With &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChromeLabs/bubblewrap&quot;&gt;bubblewrap from GoogleChromeLabs&lt;/a&gt;. It is an experimental tool that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChromeLabs/bubblewrap/tree/master/packages/cli&quot;&gt;uses a CLI&lt;/a&gt; to process your PWA and generate an apk you can upload to the play store. Let’s look at how I did it for one of my sites. Now, mrpowerscripts.com isn’t a PWA… yet. But I have many other flat Jekyll sites that are progressive web apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;progressive-web-apps-look-like-native-apps&quot;&gt;Progressive Web apps look like native apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You install a progressive web app through browsers like Chome. Not every browser supports PWAs yet, but support is growing. For instance, Firefox Mobile supports them, but Firefox Desktop, as of this date, does not. All you need to do to turn your website into a progressive web app is to add a manifest file with the details of your PWA and a service worker. Here is an example of my manifest.json file, which lives in the root of my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;ThisIsMySiteOrPWAName&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;short_name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;ThisIsShorter&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;theme_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;#39a4cd&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;background_color&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;#fff&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;prefer_related_applications&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;display&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;standalone&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;Scope&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;start_url&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/?utm_source=a2hs&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;icons&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;src&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;assets/img/favicon/manifest-icon-192.png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;sizes&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;192x192&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;image/png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;src&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;assets/img/favicon/manifest-icon-512.png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;sizes&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;512x512&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;type&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;image/png&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browsers will see this file and know that it should treat your site as a progressive web app. You also need to configure a service worker, which allows your PWA to have cool capabilities. Like offline viewing with caching, and push notifications. You know, like a native app! But this isn’t a howto on setting up a PWA. I’m assuming you already have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bubblewrap-cli&quot;&gt;The bubblewrap CLI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a site that is working as a PWA, you can start using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChromeLabs/bubblewrap/tree/master/packages/cli&quot;&gt;the bubblewrap CLI&lt;/a&gt;. Now, this may feel a bit overwhelming but stay with me here. Here are the commands you need to run to turn the PWA into an APK. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bubblewrap init --manifest https://example.com/manifest.json&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bubblewrap build&lt;/code&gt;. That’s it? That’s it. The bubblewrap CLI tool pulls in your PWA manifest file information and uses it to initialize the project. It might be a good idea to use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--directory=&lt;/code&gt; on the init as well, so it keeps everything in a folder for you. Then you can turn that folder into a git repo and track the changes. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bubblewrap build&lt;/code&gt; command takes the initialized project and uses it to build an Android APK. From there, you can treat it as a standard Android APK file. Like uploading it to the play store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you went to look at the repo, you’ll notice that there is a bit of setup because of dependencies. But it seems like this is a relatively new project that has a lot of ongoing work, so I think the dependencies will be managed better in the future. The great thing is that it works now! If you have any issues setting it up pop into &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/mrps-discord&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; and get help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-works-thanks-to-trusted-web-activity&quot;&gt;This works thanks to Trusted Web Activity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trusted web activity is an open way to verify trusted web content within an Android app. So, anything that is being opened by the mobile Chrome browser within an app. Sometimes you’ll see native apps can load web content in a browser. It’s still chrome, but apps use this feature of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/android/custom-tabs/implementation-guide&quot;&gt;Chrome Browser called Custom Tabs&lt;/a&gt;. This lets app developers make their apps open content in a browser without having to build a mobile browser themselves. It’s very convenient, and our generated APK file basically opens our PWA right into a Chrome Custom Tab instance. Then TWA tells the browser that the content is from the same developer as the app. How does the browser know that the website it’s opening is a TWA? It does this by creating a Digital Asset Links file, which like the manifest file, is accessible from your website. It would live here: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://example.com/.well-known/assetlinks.json&lt;/code&gt; Here’s an example &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;assetlinks.json&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/android/trusted-web-activity/quick-start#creating-your-asset-link-file&quot;&gt;Google’s TWA Quickstart guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-json highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;relation&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;delegate_permission/common.handle_all_urls&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;target&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;namespace&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;android_app&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;package_name&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;com.appspot.pwa_directory&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;&quot;sha256_cert_fingerprints&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;FA:2A:03:CB:38:9C:F3:BE:28:E3:CA:7F:DA:2E:FA:4F:4A:96:F3:BC:45:2C:08:A2:16:A1:5D:FD:AB:46:BC:9D&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;4F:FF:49:FF:C6:1A:22:E3:BB:6F:E6:E1:E6:5B:40:17:55:C0:A9:F9:02:D9:BF:28:38:0B:AE:A7:46:A0:61:8C&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;

    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created that file through a tool in their quickstart guide called &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Peter's Asset Link Tool&lt;/code&gt;. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=dev.conn.assetlinkstool&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;download Peter’s Asset Link Tool&lt;/a&gt; from the Play store. After publishing a Beta version of the app to the play store and downloading it, I was able to use that tool to generate the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;assetlinks.json&lt;/code&gt; file and add it to my site. So when the generated APK opens my PWA using Chrome, it knows that I made the app because of the fingerprint on my website. My content is therefor trusted and granted special abilities like being full screen in the custom tab. Otherwise, you would see the chrome toolbar at the top. Similar to when you see other native apps open a custom tab browser. So it’s a website disguised as a PWA disguised as a native app. It’s pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWA’s brought a lot of power to websites on native devices, and TWA with fancy new tools is further blurring the line between web and native applications. In this case, I only need one code base and my responsive site works on Desktop, tablets, mobile devices, Play store, and many more interfaces thanks to simple web conventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it out!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">Do you have a Progressive Web App (PWA) that you would love to see in Google’s Android play store? You can make that happen today! With bubblewrap from GoogleChromeLabs. It is an experimental tool that uses a CLI to process your PWA and generate an apk you can upload to the play store. Let’s look at how I did it for one of my sites. Now, mrpowerscripts.com isn’t a PWA… yet. But I have many other flat Jekyll sites that are progressive web apps.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">U need 2 Iterate. You need to iterate. Iteration is necessary.</title><link href="https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="U need 2 Iterate. You need to iterate. Iteration is necessary." /><published>2020-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T20:31:49+00:00</updated><id>https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mrpowerscripts.com/iteration/">&lt;p&gt;So I posted the &lt;a href=&quot;/best-blog-post-ever/&quot;&gt;best blog post ever&lt;/a&gt; the other day. And it challenged anyone who disagreed with the notion that it’s the best blog post to tell me why so that I could make it better. Now the point was to highlight two critical components to successful growth more so than profess that it’s the best blog post ever. I mean, is it REALLY the best blog post ever? Yes, obviously. It says so in the title, why wouldn’t it be true? But that isn’t the point of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that growth comes from iteration and feedback. And you need to keep doing that over and over again. When do you stop? Never. Unless you’ve built a video game about digging digital dirt blocks and sold it for 4 billion dollars. At that point, you’ve won the game. You can stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more often you iterate on some “thing,” and the more you analyze the results of that iteration and use it to guide future iterations, the better your future results could be. Oh my gosh, doesn’t that sound like machine learning? Oh my gosh, guess what? You’re a machine too! A squishy fleshy machine that may or may not enjoy watching SpongeBob Squarepants because that’s easier than failing over and over again. Computers don’t have an ego, so they’re a bit more open to the criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s simply part of the iteration process. Fucking up a lot is a great way to find out what works best and what doesn’t. Every single time you identify a crosswalk or a bus in those Google ReCaptchas, you’re essentially judging a machine at how well it was able to guess the object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“oh, hello, random human. Look at all these traffic light pictures I’ve selected for you! aren’t they wonderful?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then you correct the little machine robot tried its best, and Google uses that feedback to build a more reliable robot. Wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what machine? It’s the same for you. Want to get good at something. Start doing it. Try. Fail a lot. Keep trying. Learn from those mistakes. In the pursuit of perfection &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/quantity-always-trumps-quality/&quot;&gt;quantity always trumps quality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to be a great artist? Start drawing. Now. Find places you can share it online. Listen to that criticism. You don’t have to agree or accept everything. And that’s part of the challenge with feedback. Not all of it is good. But if you can learn how to dig through the feedback mountain, you learn to find the gems from it.  I still struggle with this a lot, but I know it’s the truth. Not everything is as simple as identifying a bus or a car in a picture. But with enough iterations, you’ll develop your intuitions, and those will help you figure out what sort of feedback can add or subtract value. Oh my goodness, the process of iteration and feedback loops works on learning how to receive feedback as well??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think this idea of developing quick iteration and feedback loops is critical for successful growth across pretty much everything. If you’re a software company that can push updates and then receives feedback quickly from users - guess what? You’re going to develop much better software a lot faster than companies who can’t. Another thought - guess who is going to have a better jump shot? Someone who practices every day or practices once a week? Practice makes perfect isn’t a new concept. It’s been around long before any of us have bee been born. I’m going to throw three bits of info that I think is super important for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write shit down. Analyze yourself. Go back and read old things you wrote. Old songs you sang, pictures you drew, software you programmed, workout tapes you recorded. You get the picture. Can you spot things you can improve? Can you build a better version of your past works? Test yourself often. Stay sharp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find people who share your growth interests. I have people from all kinds of backgrounds who I regularly contact for feedback, and when they come to me, I provide the same assistance. One of the areas I reach out to friends about is design. I’m a terrible designer, but I’m worlds ahead of where I was years ago. Thanks to the time they shared with me providing critical feedback in their area of expertise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build your intuitions. When you’ve iterated enough on something, your brain will develop shortcuts. It can happen with hobbies, career skills, whatever. You won’t have to think as much to perform them efficiently. You will find yourself in a &lt;a href=&quot;/mindfulness-meditation-flow/&quot;&gt;state of flow&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to jump in and complete tasks without wasted effort. That is where you want to find yourself, and you do it through iterating and analyzing those results to improve the next attempt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn a lot from yourself and others, but when you begin feeling confident in taking action, that’s when the real fun begins. But to get there, and achieve excellent results, sometimes it takes a bit of luck. But even luck can’t save you if you don’t try.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MrPowerScripts</name></author><category term="mrpowerscripts" /><summary type="html">So I posted the best blog post ever the other day. And it challenged anyone who disagreed with the notion that it’s the best blog post to tell me why so that I could make it better. Now the point was to highlight two critical components to successful growth more so than profess that it’s the best blog post ever. I mean, is it REALLY the best blog post ever? Yes, obviously. It says so in the title, why wouldn’t it be true? But that isn’t the point of it.</summary></entry></feed>